(WELCOME TO THE BLACK PARADE
BY MY CHEMICAL ROMANCE PLAYS)
快速停止
杂货店
♪ When I was a young boy
♪ My father took me
Into the city
♪ To see a marching band
♪ He said
"Son, when you grow up
♪ "Would you be the savior
Of the broken
♪ "The beaten and the damned?"
♪ He said
"Will you defeat them?
♪ "Your demons
And all the non-believers
♪ "The plans that
They have made?
♪ "Because one day
I'll leave you
♪ "A phantom to lead you
♪ "In the summer
To join the black parade"
如果您打算入店偷窃 请告诉我们 谢谢
报纸（还记得吗？）
现煮咖啡
♪ When I was a young boy
♪ My father took me
Into the city
薄荷口香糖
♪ To see a marching band
♪ He said
"Son, when you grow up
逝者安息 在爱的回忆中
丽贝卡斯科特希克斯 1978 - 2006
♪ "Would you be the savior
Of the broken
♪ "The beaten and the damned?"
(INSTRUMENTAL BREAK PLAYING)
♪ Sometimes I get the feeling
♪ She's watching over me
♪ And other times
I feel like I should go
♪ And through it all
The rise and fall
♪ The bodies in the streets
暂时关闭
第一局后才开业
♪ And when you're gone
We want you all to know
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
♪ We'll carry on
♪ And though
You're dead and gone
♪ Believe me
Your memory will carry on
(ALL CHEERING)
Yes!
耶！
♪ We'll carry on
♪ And in my heart
I can't contain it
♪ The anthem won't explain it
♪ A world that
Sends you reeling
♪ From decimated dreams...
-去你妈的！
-过来一个人
Fuck you!
Somebody get over here.
后补！后补！
Back up! Back up!
♪ So paint it black
And take it back
♪ Let's shout it loud and clear
♪ Defiant to the end
We hear the call
♪ To carry on
♪ We'll carry on
♪ And though
You're dead and gone
♪ Believe me
Your memory will carry on
♪ We'll carry on
♪ And though you're broken
And defeated
♪ Your weary widow marches
♪ On and on we carry
Through the fears
(MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
♪ Disappointed faces
Of your peers
好 都散开 准备好了吗？
All right.
Spread out.
Ready?
♪ 'Cause I could not
Care at all
♪ Do or die
You'll never make me
♪ Because the world
Will never take my heart
♪ Go and try
You'll never break me
♪ We want it all
We wanna play this part
♪ I won't explain or say
I'm sorry
♪ I'm unashamed
I'm gonna show my scar
♪ Give a cheer
For all the broken
♪ Listen here
Because it's who we are
(EXCLAIMS)
Whoo!
♪ Just a boy
Who had to sing this song
♪ I'm just a man
I'm not a hero
(CHEERING)
♪ I don't care
♪ We'll carry on
(ALL CHEERING)
♪ Believe me
♪ Your weary widow
Marches on ♪
(SONG FADES)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
猪肉卷 鸡蛋和奶酪
JAY:
♪ Pork roll
Egg and cheese
猪肉卷 鸡蛋和什么？
♪ Pork roll
Egg and what?
猪肉卷 鸡蛋和奶酪
♪ Pork roll
Egg and cheese
猪肉卷 鸡蛋和什么？
♪ Pork roll
Egg and what? ♪
Uh, uh, uh.
(SOMETHING'S GOT TO GIVE
BY ROOTS OF MINE PLAYING)
打扰一下
Excuse me.
有没有人在工作或
Yo, is anybody
working or, uh...
你知道你想要什么吗？
You know what
you want or what?
是的 可以给我三根史怒根烟吗？
Yeah. Can I get three
Snoogans Prerolls?
(MUTTERING)
100美元
$100 even.
是的
Right.
♪ Tell me who
Tell me who...
你能...？
Can you...
♪ Profits off the life
Of every dude
♪ Every sick
小心点
(SHUSHING)
Keep it down.
♪ Ask the schools
(BOTH WHISTLING)
♪ Break the chains
Reveal the lies... ♪
(FAKE SNEEZES)
(JAY MUTTERING)
是的
JAY: Yeah,
yeah, yeah.
看什么呢 伙计？
What 'cha
looking at, man?
这是我们在90年代的做法 小伙子！
That's how we did it
in the '90s, son!
(ALL WHISTLING HAPPY TUNE)
等等
Wait. Wait,
wait, wait.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
(COLTRANE WHISTLES)
吹着口哨会影响搬运
Your whistling
is affecting
your carrying.
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
这计划真不错啊
Pretty nifty
planning.
(WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY)
(SNICKERING)
什么鬼？
The fuck?
Oh, uh... well,
'cause, um,
好吧 你说的话让我们想到了NFT
nifty is slang
for NFT,
也就是我们世界中不可替代的代币
which is a non-fungible
token in our world.
我们的世界？
(SCOFFS)
"Our world"?
哦 上帝 我就知道
Oh, my God,
I knew it.
你们是那些在自杀前都穿着运动鞋睡觉的
You belong to one
of these religious
death cults
宗教死亡邪教的成员
where they all wear
sneakers to bed
before they
kill themselves.
最后再说一次 兰德尔
我没有加入死亡邪教
For the last
time, Randal,
I'm not in
a religious
death cult.
区块链科尔特兰和我是
Blockchain Coltrane
and I are co-founders
基督教加密货币俱乐部的联合创始人
of the Christian
Crypto Club.
(HEAVY METAL MUSIC PLAYING)
基督教加密货币俱乐部
♪ Rip and tear! ♪
这要么是《指环王》的事情
要么是耶稣的事情
This is either
a Lord of the
Rings  thing
or a Jesus thing.
Hmm.
(WHISPERING)
(SNICKERS)
(ELIAS CHUCKLING)
区块链说耶稣拯救灵魂
Blockchain says that
Jesus saves souls,
但我们购买灵魂 这是
but we buy souls,
it's... (SPUTTERS)
这是非常聪明的文字游戏
It's pretty
clever wordplay
因为梦幻链的加密货币单位
because the
Phantasma Chain's
cryptocurrency unit
被称为灵魂 所以
is called
the Soul, so...
(CHUCKLING) It's...
这...你一大早就要杀了我 你这个疯子
You are killing me
this morning,
you nut.
Oh, shit,
妈的 我想我现在明白了
I think I get it now.
明白什么？非同质化代币和加密货币？
Get what?
NFTs and crypto?
不 不是豆豆宝宝的废话
No, not that
Beanie Baby
bullshit.
是说这两个人
Talking about
this pair of puds.
看起来伊莱亚斯有自己的沉默鲍勃
Looks like Elias
has got his own
Silent Bob.
Oh, this is quite
a handjob.
这手活不错
什么？
What?
天啊 这些Z世代的孩子都完蛋了
Jesus, these Gen Z
kids are fucked.
真是个惊喜
ELIAS: Oh,
what a surprise.
兰德尔又一次妄称上帝的名字 但丁先生
Randal has taken
the Lord's name
in vain again, Mr. Dante.
请不要再叫我但丁先生了
Please stop calling me
Mr. Dante.
你已经36岁了
You're 36-years-old.
而不是无缘无故
And not for nothing,
但如果我不是向你们的基督教上帝祈祷
but how's it taking
the Lord's name in vain
如何妄称主的名呢？
if I don't pray
to your Christian God?
如果你不向上帝祈祷 那么你向谁祈祷？
If you don't pray to God,
then who do you pray to?
当我处于最低谷时 我总是向克罗姆祈祷
When I'm at my lowest,
I always pray to Crom.
谁是克罗姆？
Who's Crom?
-那是《野蛮人柯南》里的神
-你知道吗 兰德尔？
That's Conan
the Barbarian's God.
ELIAS: You know
what, Randal?
我真希望你们不崇拜那些虚假漫画偶像
I really wish
you didn't
worship all your
false comic book idols
and satanic superheroes.
和邪恶的超级英雄
蝙蝠侠 复仇者联盟 神奇女侠
亚历山大奥卡西奥科尔特斯
Batman, The Avengers,
Wonder Woman, AOC.
来吧 伙计 给克罗姆一个机会
Come on, man,
give Crom a chance.
他虽然不比耶稣
He may not be all woke
and shit like Jesus,
但对于神来说他很酷的
but homeboy's
pretty metal
for a deity.
好吧 兰德尔 你在开玩笑吧
因为只有一位上帝
Well, joke's on you,
Randal, because
there's only one God.
是嘛 托尔呢？托尔是神
Yeah. What about Thor?
Thor's a god.
托尔是一个穿越外太空的虚构人物
Thor is a fictional
character who flies
through outer space.
你的上帝也是
(SCOFFS)
So is your God.
Mr. Dante.
-但丁先生
-他的上帝是永生的基督 兰德尔
His God is the living
Christ, Randal.
他的上帝像《活死人》里的那样
有着各种哥特式特征 就比如说
His God is
the Living Dead
with all that
goth-y shit like,
喝我的血
drink my blood.
That's fucking
vampire talk.
那是他妈的吸血鬼
-但丁先生！
-不！
Mr. Dante!
Oh, no.
我的名字是富富
这是你们两个之间的事
My name is Foo-Foo
and this is between
you two.
(SCOFFS)
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, freeze.
别动
这些都是什么鬼？
What the fuck
are these?
-风筝
-不是吧
Kites.
No shit.
但它们在这里做什么？
But what are they
doing here?
我以为我们可以卖掉它们
I thought we could
sell them.
你是认真的吗？谁他妈还放风筝了？
Are you serious?
Who the fuck flies
kites anymore?
很多人
Lots of people.
现在的孩子们喜欢放风筝
Kids today love
flying kites.
Kites are cool.
风筝很酷
这都什么世纪了 本富兰克林
What century
is this,
Ben Franklin,
在这个时代什么样的孩子
and what kind of kid
in this day and age
would be
remotely interested
会对购买或放风筝感兴趣？
in buying or flying
a fucking kite?
你看到这上面有耶稣吗？
Did you see they have
Jesus on them?
哦 好吧 所有的孩子都爱耶稣
Oh, well,
all the kids
love Jesus.
有谁会买你那令人毛骨悚然的基督风筝？
Who in their
right mind
is gonna buy
one of your creepy
Christ kites?
我会
I would.
(SCOFFS)
You did, like,
30 times.
你确实买了30次
也许我们可以在网上卖一些
Maybe we can
sell some online.
线上？让互联网上的任何人
RANDAL: Online?
The only way anyone
on the Internet
关心这种老废物的唯一方法是
would care about
this old-timey bullshit
你拍摄了一个抖音短视频
is if you shot
a TikTok
trying to jam
试图将其中一个耶稣风筝
塞进你的基督教菊花内
one of those Jesus
kites up your
Christian dickhole.
(BOTH GIGGLING)
-混蛋
-谢谢
Asshole.
Thank you.
你知道吗 兰德尔？我不认为
You know what, Randal?
I don't think
there's anything
亵渎神灵有多酷
particularly "metal"
about blasphemy.
Shah, blasphemy
and biting off
a bat's head
亵渎神灵和咬掉蝙蝠的头
都像金属一样酷
are as metal
as it gets.
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
有两个与耶稣同钉十字架的人 兰德尔
There were two men
who were crucified
with Jesus, Randal.
他妈的
(SIGHS) Holy fuck.
一个好小偷和一个坏小偷
A good thief
and a bad thief.
如果他们被抓住了
我会说这让他们两个都是坏小偷
If they were caught,
I'd say
that makes them both
bad thieves.
坏小偷说
The bad thief said,
”如果你真的是上帝的儿子”
"If you are really
the son of God,
”那就让我们从这里下来”
"get us down from here
and save us."
”然后拯救我们”
那为什么这个人会被称为”坏小偷”呢？
So why is this
guy called
"The bad thief"?
称他为”具有常识的实用小偷”
Call him "The practical
thief with common
fucking sense."
Ah. But the good
thief said,
但是好小偷说
”耶稣没有做错 而我们不过是贼”
"Jesus did no wrong,
whereas we are but thieves."
偷屁贼是什么鬼？
What the fuck
are butt thieves?
Uh, well,
then the good
thief said,
好吧 然后好小偷说
“耶稣 在你的王国里记住我”
"Jesus, remember me
in your kingdom."
耶稣对好小偷说
And Jesus said
to the good thief,
“今天 你将在天堂与我同在”
"Today, you shall be
with me in paradise."
天堂是一个脱衣舞俱乐部
And Paradise
is a strip club.
不是脱衣舞俱乐部 兰德尔
It's not a strip
club, Randal.
是天堂
It's Heaven.
(SCOFFS)
所以你永无止境的故事的寓意是
So the moral of your
never ending story is,
“即使在天堂 一切都取决于你认识的人”
even in Heaven,
it's all about
who you know.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
The moral of the story
这个故事的寓意是
“如果你不是作为耶稣的客人去的天堂”
is if you didn't
go to Heaven
as a guest of Jesus,
“就像好小偷一样”
like the good thief,
坏小偷去哪儿了 兰德尔？
where did the bad
thief go, Randal?
天啊 我不是想延长你的讲道
Not that I wanna
prolong your sermon,
但是要提醒一个家伙他是上帝的儿子
这又是什么亵渎呢？
but how is it
blasphemy
to remind a guy
he's the son
of God?
也许坏小偷认为
Maybe the bad
thief thought
耶稣像《伯恩的身份》那样
Jesus had
a Bourne Identity
thing going on,
就像耶稣从船上掉下来那样
like Jesus fell
off a boat,
撞到了头然后得了失忆症
hit his head
and caught amnesia.
他出生在马槽里
He was born
in a manger.
现在他又是伯恩了
Now he's
Bourne again.
马特达蒙在伯恩诞生里
Matt Damon is
Jesus Bourne in...
饰演耶稣伯恩
The Bourne Nativity.
(CHUCKLES)
天父 我恳求你
Heavenly Father,
I beseech thee,
请打击这个咆哮的异端
please smite
this braying heretic.
(BREATHES HEAVILY) Oh.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
不 有点不对劲 我...我喘不上气来
No, something's wrong, I...
I can't catch my breath.
不要开玩笑了
Stop teasing me.
我不是在开玩笑 我
I'm not teasing, I...
我喘不上气 伙计
I can't catch
my breath, man.
真的吗？我该给你做人工呼吸吗？
Really? Should I try
mouth stuff?
这是什么 Tinder约会吗？放开我
What is this,
a Tinder date?
Get off of me.
你说你呼吸不上来
You said you
can't breathe.
我可以呼吸了 我只是
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
I can breathe. I just...
我有点喘不上气
I can't catch
my breath.
你用你的胳膊在做什么？
What are you doing
with your arm?
我在努力呼吸
I'm trying to breathe.
你都冒冷汗了 兰德尔
You're really
sweating, Randal.
这里很热 伙计 我们可以开门吗？我觉得
It's hot in here, man.
Can we open the door?
I got to...
但丁先生！
Mr. Dante!
该死！
Oh, shit!
我在快速停止需要一辆救护车
I need an ambulance
at the QuickStop.
(SIREN BLARING)
拉登海姆医生 请到急诊室
WOMAN: (OVER PA SYSTEM)
Dr. Ladenheim,
report to the ER.
Dr. Ladenheim...
你必须叫救护车 不是吗？
You had to call
an ambulance,
didn't you?
我只是在穆比餐厅吃太多了 仅此而已
I just ate too much
fuckin' Mooby's,
that's all.
好吧 如果你知道是出了什么问题
那我想我可以回家了
Well, if you know
what's wrong,
then I guess
I can go home.
你是医生吗？
Are you the doctor?
我是医生
I'm the doctor.
拉登海姆医生 今晚我会是你的救星
Dr. Ladenheim, I'll be
your savior this evening.
(CACKLING)
什么鬼？
What in the fuck?
我为我的衣着向你道歉
I apologize
for my wardrobe.
我刚参加了一个变装舞会
I just came from
a costume ball.
听着 医生 我没事 我只是
Listen, Doc,
I'm okay. I just...
我只是喘不上气 仅此而已
I can't catch
my breath is all.
按从1到10级来算 你觉得有多疼？
On a scale
of one to ten,
how bad would you say
your pain level is?
我的疼痛程度？
RANDAL:
My pain level?
大概像负三
Like a negative three.
好吧 你错了
Well, you're
doing it
all wrong.
当你心脏病发作时 应该会很痛苦
You're supposed to be
in a lot of pain
when you have
a heart attack.
等一下 我心脏病发作了？
Wait a minute.
I had a heart attack?
不 不是的 你误会了
No, that's not
what I said.
谢天谢地
You misunderstood me.
Oh, thank Christ.
You're having
a heart attack
我们说话的时候你心脏病发作了
right now
as we speak,
很严重 所以我们必须迅速采取行动
a massive one,
so we have to act
pretty quickly.
我只是希望我没有那么醉
I just wish
I wasn't
so hung over.
(SIGHS)
I'm kidding.
我在开玩笑
I'm gonna go
get all glammed up
我要去为我们的约会
打扮得漂漂亮亮的 然后在手术室见
for our big date
and I'll see you
in the OR.
看着我
Look at me.
Uh-huh.
一切都会好起来的 好吗？
Everything's gonna
be fine, all right?
-好的 好吧
-他快不行了
Good. All right.
He's not
gonna make it.
天哪 有人可以呼叫好女巫吗？
Jesus, could someone
page the Good Witch?
接下来是什么 一个他妈的芒奇金？
What's next,
a fucking Munchkin?
刮胡子和理发 25美分
(IN SING-SONG VOICE)
Shave and a haircut
two bits.
你已经见过拉登海姆医生了
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
I see that you met
Dr. Ladenheim.
她要我为你做手术准备
And she wants me to
prep you for surgery.
手术？不 医生刚刚说我只是去手术室
Surgery? No.
The doctor just said
I'm going to the OR.
对啊 就是他们做手术的地方！
Right! Which is short
for operating room
where they do...
Ding, ding, ding,
surgery!
她要打开你的心脏
She gotta get
into your heart.
医生会打开他的胸吗？
Uh, is the doctor
gonna crack
his chest open?
-操
-不
Fuck.
No, no, no.
她会通过一个很小的切口将相机
She's gonna thread
a camera through
his femoral artery
穿过他的股动脉到达心脏
up to his ticker
through a very
small incision.
她在哪里做这个切口？
Where does
she make this incision?
在腹股沟
In the groin.
The groin?
Come on.
-腹股沟？
-不是吧
所以我要给你刮毛
So I gotta shave you.
(ELECTRIC SHAVER BUZZING)
或者我给你刮胡子
Or I get
to shave you,
取决于你有多爱你的工作 而我爱我的工作
depending on how much
you love your job
and I love mine.
所以 正如妻子每个星期晚上10点
看完《犯罪故事》以后 所说的那样
So, as the wife
says at 10:00 p.m.
after Dateline,
every single week,
“把裤子脱了”
take off your pants.
(ELECTRIC SHAVER BUZZING)
(SIGHS)
我要剃你的腹股沟上的毛 先生
所以内裤也要脱了
I gotta shave
your groin, sir,
so underwear too.
首先 我们可以建立起位置吗？
First, can we
establish geography?
比如 你觉得腹股沟在哪里？
Like, where is
the groin to you?
我觉得腹股沟在哪里？
Where's the groin
to me?
这是什么 一个形而上学的问题？
What is this,
a metaphysical question?
救你一命的时间不多了 所以来吧 快点
We're running
out of time here
to save your life.
So come on,
let's go.
(ELECTRIC SHAVER BUZZING)
你能不能看向别处 堵住你的耳朵
然后唱点什么好吗？
Can you avert
your eyes,
block your ears
and sing something,
please?
-哦 看在上帝的份上
-你想让我唱什么？
Oh, for God sakes.
What do you
want me to sing?
-不是你 他
-哦 对
Not you, him.
Oh, right.
好的 是这样的 杰基护士
All right,
here's the deal,
Nurse Jackie.
(DANTE HUMMING)
Mmm.
我有一个非常小的鸡巴 好吗？
I got a really
small dick, okay?
我向你保证 我也不是没见过
I promise you,
it's nothing
I've not seen before
因为我在儿科工作
because I work
in pediatrics.
(DANTE HUMMING)
如果我脱掉我的内裤
If I take off
my underwear,
急诊室的每个人都会看到我的小鸡巴
everyone in the ER is
gonna see my little dick
包括我的朋友
including my
friend here,
他以为我很巨大 因为我从12岁起
who thinks I got
a giant cock 'cause
I've been lying to him
about it since
we were 12.
(GRUNTS)
就一直在对他撒谎
这是一个很长的寓言吗 伊索？
Is this a long
fable, Aesop?
我会告诉你我要做什么 给你多一点隐私
I'll tell you
what I'm gonna do,
give you a little
more privacy...
-就这样
-谢谢你
There you go.
Oh, thanks for that.
不好意思 你只能跟到这里了
Unfortunately,
this is as far
as you can go
但我们有个候诊室 你直走就到了
but we do have a waiting
room that's right
down this hall.
你出来的时候我会在这里的 伙计
I'll be right here
when you get out, man.
你行的
You got this.
(SNIFFLES)
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ You got an idea
We can rock the night
我们有一名女性患有多种C脊柱并发症
PARAMEDIC:
We've got a female
with multiple
C-spine complications,
internal bleeding
内出血和多处撕裂伤
and multiple
lacerations.
血压100/70
Blood pressure,
100 over seven...
♪ Let's both make a promise
That we can't say... ♪
通知格雷医生
她快不行了 开始心肺复苏术
ER NURSE:
We're losing her.
Starting CPR.
我们已经做好准备了
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
格格雷医生 请到手术室
(INDISTINCT PA ANNOUNCEMENT)
DR. LADENHEIM: (GASPS)
Why has he still
为什么他还穿着内裤？
got his
underpants on?
他还穿着内裤
How am I supposed
to get to his
femoral artery
我怎么找得到他的股动脉？
if he's wearing
Squeezies?
我跟他说了 但他有一些身体羞耻的问题
MALE NURSE:
(SPUTTERS)
I told him,
but he's got some
body shame issues.
是这样的 医生 我有一个非常小的鸡巴
(DR. LADENHEIM SIGHS)
Look, Doc,
我想救你的命
而你还在担心你的小鸡巴？
I got a really
small dick.
I'm trying
to save your life
我们没有时间了
and you're worried
about your
little dick?
We don't have
time for this.
Whoa!
这都是我的错
(SOBBING)
This is all
my fault.
不 不是的 埃利亚斯
No, it is not, Elias.
我祈求上帝打击兰德尔
I prayed to God
to smite Randal
所以耶稣在我的祈祷下攻击了他的心脏
so Jesus
attacked his heart
at my command.
(SOBBING)
兰德尔的母亲也有心脏病
Randal's mother
had heart
trouble, too.
不 我必须让耶稣扭转这一点
(SNIFFLES) No,
I gotta make
Jesus reverse this.
和我一起祈祷吧 但丁先生
Pray with me,
Mr. Dante.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
哦 我可爱的救世主
Oh, my sweet savior,
hear your
gentle servant.
听一下你温柔的仆人吧
放过我开玩笑说的那个异端
Spare the heretic
I damned in jest.
记住好小偷的话
Remember the words
of the good thief.
耶稣没有错
Jesus did no wrong,
而我们不过是小偷
whereas we are
but thieves.
DR. LADENHEIM: A-ha.
What's up, Doc?
这是怎么回事医生？
我可以从你非常微妙的纹身看出
I can tell by your
very subtle tattoo
你是超级英雄的粉丝 所以你可能会欣慰一点
that you're
a superhero fan,
so you might
appreciate this.
你知道 他们有你现在
Uh-huh.
You know,
they have a name
for the type
心脏病发作类型的名字
of heart attack
you're having
right now.
真的吗？好的
Really? Okay.
他们称之为寡妇制造者
They call it
the Widow-Maker.
现在 这听起来不像是《危险境地》里的
主角必须对付的坏人吗？
Now, doesn't
that sound like
some bad guy
that Ranger Danger
has to fight?
(CHUCKLES)
为什么他们称它为寡妇制造者？
Why do they call it
the Widow-Maker?
因为在80%的情况下
Because in 80%
of the cases
像现在这样100%的遮挡？
when there's 100%
occlusion like what
you have now?
老实说 病人总是死去 总是
Hands down,
patient always
dies, always.
他妈的
Oh, fuck.
但别担心 你会是那20%
But don't worry,
you're gonna
be in the 20%
因为让你活着对我的名誉有好处
because keeping
you alive is good
for my brand.
现在 如果你不介意的话
Now, if you
excuse me,
我要在你的裤裆里
I'm gonna go fool around
in your little crotch
做一个小魔术
and I'm gonna make
a little magic,
但我可以利用我们能得到的所有帮助
but I could use
all the help
that we can get.
所以 如果你还记得小时候的任何祈祷词
So, if you remember
any prayers
from when you
were a kid,
现在用上它们的好时机
now would be
a terrific time
to dust those off.
(RANDAL GROANS SOFTLY)
你在吗 克罗姆？
Are you there, Crom?
是我 兰德尔
It's me, Randal.
请不要让我死
(ECHOES SLIGHTLY)
Please don't let me die.
他不会回答我的
He won't answer me.
毕竟这段时间
After all this time...
把我的生命献给上帝
devoting my life
to God.
耶稣抛弃了我们快速停止的所有人
Jesus has abandoned
all of us at QuickStop.
我认为耶稣一直更像是哇哇餐厅的人
I think Jesus
was always more
of a Wawa guy.
(SIGHS) Yeah, well,
you know what I think?
是的 好吧 你知道我的想法吗？
我想我这辈子都浪费在了相信这些垃圾上
I think I wasted
my life believing
in bullshit.
我被骗了
I've been conned.
童话 信仰和
Fairy tales, faith
and pledging fealty
向一个虚构的该死的幻影宣誓效忠 为了什么？
to a fictional
fucking phantom.
And for what?
在我最需要他的最黑暗时刻
主完全使我成为鬼魂
In my darkest hour
when I need him most,
the Lord totally
ghosts me.
见鬼去吧 那些瞎编的关于耶稣的谎言
Well, to hell
with all that
made up Jesus jive.
(NECKLACE CLATTERS)
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
Save Randal
this night,
今晚拯救兰德尔的话
我向你发誓
and I will swear
my soul to you,
可爱的撒旦
oh, sweet Satan.
撒旦？伙计 不行啊
Satan? Oh,
buddy, no.
我的意思是 他是不是有点邪恶的擎天柱？
I mean, isn't he kind
of like the Optimus
Prime of evil?
你不必对我屈尊俯就
You don't have to
condescend to me.
你可以说是威震天
You can just
say Megatron.
我有点像《变形金刚》里的处男
I'm kind of
a Transformers virgin.
这个嘛
(SIGHS) Well,
我是一个真正的处男
I'm an actual
virgin,
所以我知道撒旦会想要我的灵魂
so I know Satan's
gonna want my soul.
-为了什么？
-邪恶
For what?
Evil.
可能还有性爱吧
And butt
sex probably.
-你有润滑油吗？
-你能安静点吗？
Do you have any lube?
Are you...
不！
No!
我不值得用润滑！
(LOUDLY) I don't
deserve lube!
带我走吧 撒旦！
Take me, Satan!
天啊！把裤子穿好
Jesus! Pull up
your pants.
-让我做你的妾！
-耶稣啊
Make me
your concubine!
Jesus...
-把裤子穿好
-不 停下来
Pull up your pants.
No, stop it.
I have
to fuck Satan.
我必须操撒旦
就在那时 我不骗你
And that's when,
I shit you not,
卢克他妈的天行者出现了
Luke fuckin' Skywalker
shows up.
DR. LADENHEIM: Uh-huh.
And I'm talking about
我说的是《绝地归来》中年轻 可恶的卢克
the young, fuckable Luke
from Return of the Jedi,
不是《最后的绝地武士》中的大都灵
“离开我的草坪”卢克
not the Gran Torino,
"Get off my lawn"
Luke from The Last Jedi.
DR. LADENHEIM: Okay.
好的
说一下心脏指数 格雷夫斯先生
Quick heart update,
Mr. Graves.
Uh-huh.
During your thorough
在你彻底复述《星球大战秀》的过程中
retelling of
The Star Wars Show...
是《曼达洛人》 第二季
The Mandalorian,
season two.
我能够将支架固定到位
所以我现在需要你的帮助
...I was able to get
the stent in place.
So this is where
I need your help now.
我要打开这个支架 然后你要做的是
I'm gonna open this stent
and all you have to do
当你感到压力减轻时告诉我 好的？
is tell me
when you feel
the pressure lets up.
All right?
我们这样做吧 麦克德雷米
Let's do this, McDreamy.
“这就是道”
"This is The Way."
通往什么的道？
The way to what?
哦 这是《曼达洛人》的说法
Oh, that's a saying
from The Mandalorian.
Huh?
The Star Wars Show.
《星球大战秀》
好 听着 我们得暂停
Okay, listen,
we need to hit pause
你对所有流行文化的讨论
on all your pop culture
references for a minute
直到我们打开支架为止 我数到三
just until we open
the stent on three.
一 二 三！
One, two, three!
(GASPING)
Oh!
天哪 我他妈的又能呼吸了
Holy shit, I can
fucking breathe again.
这是否意味着我能活了？
Does this mean
I'm gonna live now?
是的 因为我是一位了不起的医生
Yes, because
I'm an amazing doctor.
你是一个比奇异博士和扎伊斯博士
加起来还更好的医生
You're a better doctor
than Doctor Strange
and Doctor Zaius
combined.
Doctor who?
什么博士？
Oh, no, I don't
watch that show,
不 我没看过
但我现在可以看了 因为我他妈的还活着
but I might start now
because I'm fucking alive.
(LAUGHS)
“恭喜了！”正如中国人所说的
"Mazel tov!"
As the Chinese say.
谢谢你 医生
Thank you, Doctor.
谢谢你救了我一命
Thank you for
saving my life.
你就像心脏手术的蝙蝠侠
You're like the Batman
of heart surgery.
(CHUCKLES)
是嘛？
Yeah?
拥有权利的同时也被赋予了重大的责任
(SPEAKING GRUFFLY)
With great power
comes great
responsibility.
那是什么鬼？
What the fuck
was that?
-你还活着
You're alive!
DANTE: You're alive!
-你还好吗？
-如果那是心脏病发作
Are you okay?
If that was
a heart attack,
我能再来一次 简直太容易了
I'll take another one.
That shit was easy.
(CHUCKLES)
好吧 你现在肯定是麻药还没醒
Okay, you must be
on a lot of drugs
right now.
不 他们没有给我任何东西
No, they didn't
give me
nothing in there.
我必须清醒地经历整个手术
I had to do
the whole
thing sober.
他对芬太尼兴奋不已
He's high as a kite
on fentanyl.
风筝意象 很酷
Kite imagery,
very cool.
看 兰德尔 风筝在空中呢
See, Randal,
kites are in the air.
别再说你妈的风筝了
Stop with the
fucking kites.
还有一件事 格雷夫斯先生
DR. LADENHEIM:
One more thing,
Mr. Graves,
since you were really
preoccupied about it,
既然你真的那么在意
以至于你浪费了时间 还差点死掉
so much so that
you wasted time
and nearly died,
你的鸡巴其实没那么小
your penis is not
that small.
它没有那么大 但也没有那么小
It's not that big,
but it's not that small.
(CHUCKLES)
That's the best
news I heard all day.
这是我一整天听到的最好的消息
(CHUCKLING WEAKLY)
他会没事的吧？
DANTE: Is he gonna
be okay?
我该如何帮助他？
How do I help?
好 如果你在乎他的话 你要让他多吃蔬菜
Well, if you care
about him,
you'll jam a vegetable
down his throat.
这家伙动脉中的胆固醇比血液还多
The guy's got more
cholesterol in his
arteries than blood.
知道了 从今以后 我只给他点
Got it. From now on,
I'm only gonna
order him food
菜单上的素食
off the vegan
menu at Mooby's.
-他和你
-我吗？
Him and you.
Me?
如果你和他的年纪差不多
并且和你的朋友有同样的饮食习惯
If you're around
his age
and eat the same diet
as your friend,
那你最好也检查一下你的心脏
you might wanna get
your heart checked out, too.
会的
Will do.
但还有一些关于兰德尔的事情我想让你留意
But here's something
I want you to keep
an eye out for
as regards to Randal.
好的
Okay.
中年男性往往在他们心脏病发作之后
Middle-aged men tend to
go through a depression
会经历抑郁症
after they've had
a heart attack.
现在你的朋友的言行举止可能会有所不同
Now your friend might
sound or act differently
now because
因为他已经面对过自己的死亡
he's come face to face
with his own mortality.
所以 在接下来的几个月里 尽你所能
So, for the next
few months,
do whatever
you can do
帮助兰德尔振作起精神
to help Randal
keep his spirits up.
好吗？
All right?
现在 我要去忙了
Now, my bill
is in the mail.
(WHATEVER IT TAKES
BY LISA DALBELLO PLAYING)
说三道四的
Judgy.
♪ Whatever it takes
♪ I know I can make it
♪ I know
I can make it through
(SONG FADES)
我给你带了一顶帽子
I brought you a hat.
是嘛 谢谢
Yeah. Thanks.
我不敢相信在你经历了这一切后还醒着
I can't believe
you're still awake
after the day
you've been through.
是的 我睡不着
Yeah, I can't sleep.
今晚我能活着出手术室的几率
There was only
a 20% chance
只有20%
I was gonna make it out
of that OR alive tonight.
Hmm. Is that right?
真的吗？
我的意思是 我觉得我每次离开公寓
都有一半的几率会死
I mean, I figure I got
a 50-50 chance of dying
any time I leave
my apartment.
但今天
But today,
对我来说
there was an 80% chance
everything for me
有80%的机会一切都会停止
was just gonna stop.
有80%的机会
There was an 80% chance
你和我再也不能谈论《星球大战》了
you and I were never
gonna talk about
Star Wars  again.
有80%的机会我永远不会知道一个医学事实
There was
an 80% chance
I would never know
for a medical fact,
那就是我有一个正常大小的鸡巴
I got a normal-sized dick.
你总是说它很大
You always said
it was huge.
如果你今天不叫救护车的话
我会失去很多东西的
I was gonna miss
a lot of shit
if you didn't call
that ambulance today.
你救了我的命 伙计
You saved
my life, man.
(CLICKS TONGUE) Oh.
我希望我有一个值得他妈的被拯救的生命
I wish I had a life
worth fucking saving.
别这样 伙计
DANTE:
Come on, man.
你在说什么？
What are you
talking about?
当我躺在那里 想着我是否会死去
When I was lying there,
wondering if
I was gonna die,
我在眼前看到了我整个人生电影
I saw the whole
movie of my life
flash before my eyes.
你知道吗？
You know what?
它糟透了
It sucked. (SCOFFS)
我一直在想 也希望
I always thought,
hoped...
我的生活朝着某种方向发展
that my life
was building
towards something.
原来就只是在医院
Turns out it was
just the hospital.
你在说什么？
What are you
talking about?
我们建立了自己的生意
We built our
own business.
所以我能共同拥有一家便利店 很了不起
So I co-own
a convenience
store. Big deal.
我从来没有去过泽西城以外的任何地方
I never went anywhere
outside of Jersey.
我从来没有像你一样坠入爱河
I never fell
in love like you.
如果今晚我就死了
If I'd have
dropped dead tonight,
只有你和埃利亚斯会记得我曾经存在过
only you and Elias would
remember I even existed.
我的意思是 看看我 伙计 我快50岁了
I mean, look
at me, man,
I'm almost 50.
我坐在那里一遍又一遍地看同样愚蠢的电影
I sit around
and watch the same
stupid movies
over and over.
(SIGHS)
我他妈怎么了？
The fuck is
wrong with me?
我不知道
I don't know.
你对所有的东西都很了解
You know so much
about all that stuff.
我一直认为你可以拍一部很酷的电影
I always thought you could
have made a cool movie.
天啊
Holy shit.
你说得没错
You're right.
我可以拍一部很酷的电影
I could make
a pretty cool movie.
我这一辈子都在看电影
I've been
watching movies
all my life,
我见过所有这些人讲述他们的故事
I've seen all
these people
tell their stories
从来没有想过要讲述我自己的
and never once
thought about
trying to tell mine.
好吧 去他妈的 伙计
Well, fuck
that, man.
既然我今晚差点死去
现在我知道我是靠借来的时间生活的
Since I almost
died tonight,
now I know I'm living
on borrowed time.
所以 不要再看电影了
So, no more
watching movies
因为当我离开这里后
because when
I get out of here...
我要拍电影！
I'm gonna make
a movie!
(MACHINE BEEPING)
电影？
DANTE: A movie?
你不需要去电影学校什么的吗？
Don't you have to go to
film school or something?
去纽约大学电影学院一年要七万五美元
It's like 75 G's a year
to go to NYU Film School.
你知道那些孩子花那么多钱是为了什么吗？
And you know what
those kids pay
all that money for?
-我不知道
-去看电影
I don't know.
To watch movies.
我在影像店工作了20年
I worked in a video
store for 20 years
我也整天坐在那儿看电影
where I sat around
and watched
movies all day, too.
所以也能说是我去了我自己的电影学校
So basically,
I went to my own
film school.
就因为你看过每一部电影
Just because you've seen
every movie ever made,
并不意味着你可以制作任何类型的电影
doesn't mean you can make
any kind of movie at all.
这话去跟昆汀塔伦蒂诺说吧
(SCOFFS) Tell that
to Quentin Tarantino.
哦 现在你是昆汀塔伦蒂诺？
Oh, now you're
Quentin Tarantino?
我不是说我要拍一部跟他一样好的电影
I'm not saying
I'm gonna make
a movie as good as him,
但我也不擅长做爱
but I'm not good
at sex either,
这并不能阻止我尝试跟别人上床
and that doesn't stop me
from trying to get laid.
(SCOFFS)
我向你保证 他还活着！
你想在这里拍电影吗？
DANTE: You wanna
shoot a movie here,
在快速停止？
at the QuickStop?
是的 我以前看过电影里的便利店
Yeah, I've seen
convenience stores
in flicks before,
但我从未看过一整部都是在便利店里拍的电影
but I've never seen
an entire flick
set in
a convenience store.
因为谁会想看呢？
Because who would
wanna watch that?
我的意思是 这是我的人生
我都不想过这样的生活
I mean, it's my life
and I barely
wanna live it.
这部电影是为了纪念我的一生
This movie's meant
to memorialize
my life.
既然我过去30年都在这里工作...
And since
I spent the last
30 years of my life
working here...
工作？
Oh. Working?
我有很多便利店的故事可以写成剧本
I got plenty of
convenience stories
to put into
a screenplay.
《便利故事》 好标题
Convenience Stories.
Good title.
那么 我们要在这里谈论什么样的“便利故事”？
Well, what kind of
convenience stories
are we talking
about here?
(LAUGHS)
Remember the time
we went to
记得我们去参加朱莉德怀尔的葬礼
Julie Dwyer's funeral
and you knocked
the casket over?
然后你把棺材打翻了？
你把棺材打翻了
You knocked
the casket over.
我吗？
I did?
(SIGHS)
嗯 这就是现在的场景
Well, that's
a scene now.
或者是那个老家伙在浴室里打飞机
Or how about the time
the old guy
was jerking off
然后突然就死掉？
in the bathroom
and dropped dead?
这完全是一个场景 伙计
That's totally
a scene, man.
我的意思是 你和我在这个柜台说的所有废话
I mean, all the shit
you and I have said
sitting at
this counter,
这些都是场景 伙计
these are all
scenes now, man.
你烧毁商店的那次怎么样？
How about the time
you burned
the store down?
会是这样的场景吗？
Is that gonna
be a scene?
我仍然很确定是恐怖分子干的
I'm still pretty sure
terrorists did that.
Uh-huh.
(DOOR OPENS)
嘿！
RANDAL: Hey, hey!
杂色圆领
Motley Crewneck.
你们的基督教加密俱乐部中有任何人
能借我们非加密相机吗？
Anyone in your
Christian Crypto Club
got a non-crypto camera
we can borrow?
它现在被称为赤红加密俱乐部了
It's called
the Crimson
Crypto Club now.
加密风筝将是我们的第一发
Our first drops
gonna be all
crypto kites.
把那些狗屎收起来 埃隆穆史克拉特
Oh, put that
shit away,
Elon Muskrat.
-你们需要相机做什么？
-兰德尔想拍电影
What do you guys
need a camera for?
RANDAL: Mmm.
Randal wants
to make a movie.
色情电影？
Ooh, like
a pornography movie?
不 就正经电影 有演员和剧本
No, like
a movie-movie,
one with actors
and a screenplay
和伙食
and Crafty. (LAUGHS)
什么是伙食？
What's Crafty?
那是所有人一起吃喝玩乐
That's where the,
uh, crew hangs out
和练习巫术的地方 你这个小恶魔崇拜者
and practices
witchcraft,
you little
devil worshipper.
酷
Cool.
伙食部是在片场能找到所有食物的地方
Crafty is where
you find all
the food on set.
但如果你在这里拍摄
我猜整个店都是伙食部
But if you're
shooting in here,
I guess the whole
store's Crafty.
电影是关于什么？
What's the movie
gonna be about?
大概一个半小时 我讨厌长电影
Mmm, it's gonna
be about an hour
and a half.
I hate long movies.
这是关于他在这里工作的故事
It's about him
working here.
ELIAS: Wow.
多元
Meta. Never seen
a whole movie
以前从未看过整部都在便利店的电影
set in
a convenience
store before.
是吧？谢谢你
Right? Thank you.
我会把我和但丁这么多年来
I'm gonna fill
the script with
all the weird shit
在这里说过或看到的所有奇怪的东西写进剧本
me and Dante
have ever said
or seen around here
over the years.
Oh.
你应该把你曾经说过
You should put
in that stuff
you used to say
关于死星承包商的东西放进去
about the Death Star
contractors.
(SCOFFS)
Get sued by Disney?
Fuck that.
被迪士尼起诉？去他妈的
再说了 我不希望这部电影是关于其他电影的
Besides, I don't want
this movie to be about
other movies.
I want it to
be about me.
我希望它是关于我的
这是我的电影 所以我想写下我所做的事情
It's my flick,
so I wanna write about
the things that I do.
就像我们在屋顶上打曲棍球一样
Like, um, like how
we play hockey
on the rooftop.
我从未在电影或电视节目中看到过
I've never seen
that done in a movie
or a TV show,
即使这很实用
even though
it's just
fucking practical.
还记得我用面包打你脸的那次吗？
(LAUGHS) Remember
that fight
where I hit you
in the face
with the bread?
那可以是一个场景
Ooh, that could
be a scene.
或是我向那个老家伙吐水的那次？
Or the time
I spit water
on that old guy?
那就是 就像 他妈的开场
That's, like,
the fucking
opening scene.
我有个主意
Ooh, I got an idea.
也许杰和沉默的鲍勃可以成为角色
Maybe Jay and
Silent Bob
could be characters.
这是我听过的最愚蠢的想法
That is the
dumbest idea
I've ever heard.
好吧 如果你想在你的旧影像店设置任何场景
DANTE: Well,
you're still
gonna have
to get them involved
if you wanna set
你仍然需要让他们参与进来
any of the scenes
in your old video store.
好吧 先记着
All right.
Watch the
register, dawg.
我们得去和华纳兄弟谈谈
We got to go talk
to the Warner
Brothers.
如果您打算入店偷窃 吃我的鸡巴
What the fuck, man?
We heard you died.
什么鬼 伙计？我们听说你死了
差点 事实是 我正在高高的草丛中拉屎
Almost.
What happened
is I was taking a shit
in the high grass
一条响尾蛇跑过来咬了我的屁眼
when a rattlesnake
came up
and bit me right
on the asshole.
但作为好朋友
But like the good
friend he is,
但丁把毒吸了出来
Dante sucked
the poison out.
看？这也发生在他们身上 伙计
See? It happened
to them, too, man.
听着 当我们以为你死了的时候 伙计
Well, listen,
when we thought
you were dead, man,
我感觉非常非常糟糕
I felt really,
really bad
因为一直以来我都在闲逛
'cause in all the time
I've been hanging out
在这家商店面前
in front of this
store and stuff,
我忘了给你点东西
I forgot to give
you something.
《牙科学校》？
Dental School?
我和菜屌在1994年租了那个东西
Me and Veggie Dick
rented that shit
in 1994,
但我们从未看过
but we never
watched it
因为我们没有录像机
'cause we didn't
have a VCR.
(CHUCKLES)
但是现在 你可以把它放在影像店的货架上
But now,
you can put it
on the shelf
in the video store.
Oh, yeah.
Uh, the video
store closed
ten years ago.
这家店十年前关门了
是吗？
It did?
就是这里
This was the
video store.
哦 是的 我越来越健忘了
就在那里 你知道吗？
Oh, yeah,
I'm getting senile
and shit right there,
you know? (LAUGHS)
那这样 我们欠你多少滞纳金？
So listen,
how much we owe
you for late fees?
(SCOFFS) Uh, well,
let's see, a dollar
a day for what,
好吧 让我们看看 一天一美元的话
26 28年？
26, 28 years?
也就是 大概
That's, like,
approximately...
$10,220.
10220美元
他们没有倒带
Oh, didn't rewind.
10220.50美元
$10,220 and 50 cents.
你收加密货币吗？
You take crypto?
你们有加密货币？
You guys got crypto?
没有
No.
如果你没看过
If you never
watched it,
-为什么不倒带？
-对啊
why was it
not rewound?
Yeah.
嘿 混蛋 我说了我们没有录像机
Hey, asshole,
I said we didn't
have a VCR.
我们看过
We watched it.
We held it up
to the light.
我们把它举到光下
蠢货
(CHUCKLES)
Fucking Luddite.
听着 如果你让我们在这里拍电影
Listen, we'll squash
your giant late fees
on the 28-year-old copy
of Dental School
那滞纳金我们就不要了
if you let us shoot
a movie in here.
色情电影？
Ooh, a pornography
movie?
不 不是色情电影
No, it's not
a porno movie.
那种能卖 兄弟 我一直在买
Sex sells, son,
and I'm always buying
因为我是阴蒂指挥官！
'cause I am
the Clit Commander!
来吧婊子们
Snootchie Bootchies.
(7-ELEVEN NACHOS
BY FROGGY PLAYING)
♪ I love nachos
♪ Nachos from 7-Eleven
♪ I know that
They're bad for me
♪ When I eat them
I'm in heaven
♪ 7-Eleven nachos!
♪ Liquid toppings
Taste so good ♪
晚安
Goodnight.
37？
Thirty-seven?
那不是场景 兰德尔
That's not
a scene, Randal.
现在别写了
Stop writing it
right now.
37不能写进你的电影
Thirty-seven cannot go
in your movie.
他妈的闭嘴 现在是晚上！
(SHOUTING)
Shut the fuck up.
It's nighttime!
《便利》？
DANTE: "In Convenience"?
这是我一生的故事
It's the story
of my life.
168页的鸡巴笑话
Hundred and
sixty-eight pages
full of dick jokes,
背景设在便利店 一晚上写的
set in
a convenience store,
written in one night.
也许不要告诉人们最后一部分
Maybe don't
tell people
that last part.
我以为 你会称它为《便利故事》
I thought, you were
gonna call it
"Convenience Stories."
是的 这听起来太珍贵了
Yeah, that
shit sounded
too precious.
我是什么 韦斯安德森？
What am I,
Wes Anderson?
不是基于这个剧本
(CHUCKLES) Not based
on this script.
“只有一次回归”
"There is only
one return
“不是国王的 是绝地的”
"and it ain't
of the King,
it's of the Jedi."
嘿
Hmm.
ELIAS: Hey.
那个家伙在餐厅吐的那天你也说了同样的话
You said that
same thing
about return
the day that
guy threw up
in Mooby's
-你让我把它清理干净
-是的
and you made
me clean it.
RANDAL: Yeah.
剧本中的一切都是我或我认识的人所说的
Everything
in the script
is something
either me or someone
I know said,
我只是编了新名字
I just made up
new names.
我是什么 某种作家？
What am I,
some kind of writer?
是的
(WHISPERING)
Ah, yes.
区块链想了解
Blockchain
would like
to understand
为什么这两个女孩都喜欢这个叫丹T的角色
why the two girls
are into this
"Dan-T" character
但是兰迪角色更有趣
when the Randy
character is
much funnier.
兰迪一生都在问自己同样的问题
Randy has been
asking himself
the same question
his whole life.
丹T怎么了？
What's wrong
with Dan-T?
(SCOFFS)
读他在第3页的第一个场景
Read his first scene
on page 37.
你在开玩笑吧？
DANTE: Are you
kidding me?
我比你在便利店里的时间更长
I'm in this
convenience store
way more than you,
但是我怎么到了第37页
才出现在你的便利店电影里？
but I don't come
into your
convenience store
movie 'til page 37?
我有很多事情要做
I had a lot of
exposition to do.
“丹T上”
(SIGHS) "Enter Dan-T.
“一个可怕的他妈的混蛋” 他妈的什么？
"A hideous fuckin'
chud of a man."
What the fuck?
好吧 也许丹T不是你
RANDAL: Well,
maybe Dan-T's not you.
你有没有想过？
Do you ever
think of that?
“丹T留着可怕的胡须”
"Dan-T's
hideous fuckin'
chud of a beard
“与其说是托尼斯塔克”
"doesn't suggest Tony
Stark so much as
a male crack whore
“不如说是一个扮演托尼斯塔克的疯男人”
"who is cosplaying
as Tony Stark."
那只是在剧情方向
That's just
in the screen
direction.
没有人当着他的面说
丹T是“一个可怕的混蛋”
Nobody actually
calls Dan-T
"a hideous
fuckin' chud."
To his face.
我不敢相信你让我签署了一份保密协议
I can't believe
you made me
sign a non-disclosure
agreement,
结果却发现我甚至
only to read that
I'm not even
不是你生活故事中的主角之一
one of the main
characters in the
story of your life.
我是说 我知道我从来都不是卢克
但我认为我至少是汉
I mean, I knew
I was never the Luke,
but I thought
I was at least
the Han.
拜托 我是汉也是卢克 对吧？
Oh, come on,
I'm the Han
and the Luke,
right?
(SCOFFS)
那我是谁 小楚？
Then who am I,
the Chewie?
我认为埃利亚斯更像是小楚 不是吗？
I think Elias is more
the Chewie, no?
除非这是帝国 否则我是兰多 他是洛博特
Unless this is Empire
then I'm the Lando
and he's the Lobot.
我甚至连洛博特都不是？
I'm not even
the Lobot?
哪个是洛博特？
Which one's Lobot?
他是那个戴着耳机
He's the one with
the headphones
who looks like
看起来像是想当DJ的老爹的人
a dad who's trying
to be a DJ.
那个秃头混蛋贝斯平在整部电影中一句话都没说
The bald fucker
from Bespin
who never
says nothing
the whole movie.
这样沉默鲍勃不就是洛博特吗？
Wouldn't that make
Silent Bob the Lobot?
不 杰伊和沉默鲍勃显然是C-3PO和R2-D2
No. Jay and Silent
Bob are clearly the
C-3PO and R2-D2.
我的意思是 他们从第一部电影开始就一直在
I mean, they've
been here since
the first movie,
那是他们以前很酷的时候
which was
the last time
they were cool,
但他们已经合作了这么长时间
but they've been
with the franchise
so long
仍然会让他们客串 并把他们印在午餐盒上
they still give
them cameos
and put them
on the lunchboxes.
所以如果我不是卢克、汉、小楚、兰多
So if I'm not
Luke, Han,
Chewie, Lando,
机器人或洛博特
the droids
or the Lobot,
那我他妈在你的《星球大战》里是谁
then who the fuck
am I in your
Star Wars,
-他妈的莱娅公主？
-不
Princess
fucking Leia?
No.
你是达克
You're the Dak.
达克到底是谁？
Who the fuck is Dak?
他是霍斯战役中卢克天行者的尾炮手
He's Luke Skywalker's
tail gunner
in the Battle of Hoth.
就是那个准备亲自对付整个帝国
You know,
the guy who's ready
to take on the whole
Empire himself
直到帝国把他干掉的家伙？
until the Empire kills
the shit out of him?
(SCOFFS) Did Dak
even get an
action figure?
达克有被做成活动玩偶吗？
不在经典的肯纳系列中
Not in the classic
Kenner line, no.
因为？
Because?
因为人们认为他在这个故事中不重要
Because he was
deemed unimportant
to the story.
但那只是胡说八道 伙计
没有达克 卢克永远不会
But that's just
bullshit, man.
Without Dak,
Luke could
have never...
达克是唯一一个
Like, Dak was
the only guy
that's, like, uh...
我的意思是 达克贼勇敢 伙计 就像你一样
I mean, Dak was
plucky as shit, man,
just like you.
我有一个关于剧本的问题
Uh, I have a question
about the script.
太棒了 要有他妈的更多笔记了
Great, more
fuckin' notes.
Go ahead.
ELIAS: Yes.
-说吧
-是
我对修道士这个角色有意见
Uh, I have a problem
with the Friar
Fuck character,
我相信 应该是我的角色吧
who, I believe,
is supposed to be me.
他妈的修道士爱耶稣
Friar Fuck, uh,
loves Jesus,
uh, to what appears to
be an unhealthy degree.
到了看起来不健康的程度
然后呢？
And?
埃利亚斯是一个重生的撒旦教徒
And Elias is a born
again Satanist.
因为是撒旦拯救了你
Because it was Satan
who saved you
当大混蛋耶稣对我的祈祷
when my prayers
fell on the deaf
ears of Jesus,
充耳不闻时
the giant jerkoff.
(SPITTING)
好吧 听着 修道士
All right,
listen up,
Friar Fuck.
我知道你最近刚刚和男朋友耶稣分手了
I get that you
just broke up
with your boyfriend
Jesus recently,
很明显你因此开始改变
and clearly you're
going through
some couture
你的时装和妆容
and cosmetic stuff
because of it.
但在你生命的前36年里
But for the
first 36 years
of your life,
you were into Jesus
to an unhealthy degree,
你对耶稣的喜爱程度已经很不健康了
而这就是以修道士为原型的埃利亚斯
and that's the Elias
that I based
Friar Fuck on.
那么这个剧本是基于谎言的
Then this script
is based on lies.
欢迎来到电影界
Welcome to
the movie biz.
这门艺术没有真理！
There's no truth
in this art!
耶稣
Jesus.
每个人都是批评家
Everyone's a critic.
那么 我们接下来要做什么？
So, what do
we do next?
你问达克干什么？
What are you
asking Dak for?
好吧 我一个人做不了 我需要一个制片人
Well, I can't do this alone.
I need a producer.
-那是你的工作
-我？
That's your job.
Me?
我又不怎么懂制片
What do I know
about producing?
我都已经在编剧和导演了
Come on. I'm already
writing and directing.
我不能什么都做 伙计
I can't do
everything, man.
好吧 制作人是做什么的？
All right. What does
a producer do?
只需为我们制定一个时间表
将我们控制在预算范围内
Just build us a schedule,
keep us under budget,
secure a DP,
and most importantly,
找个摄影导演 最重要的是 为我们找到融资
find us financing.
什么 我还要找人融资？
What, I gotta
get money, too?
我们在这里说的是多少？
How much are we
talking about here?
Mmm, 25 grand.
2万5千美元
2万5千美元？
$25,000?
严格来说 应该是27575美元
Well, technically,
it's $27,575
但如果我们在加拿大的话那就更多了
but it would be way more
if we were in Canada.
我他妈的应该从哪里找到那种钱？
Where the fuck
am I supposed to find
that kind of
money from?
我们可以找到那种现金
We can find that
kind of cash.
什么？如何？
What? How?
我们下个月推出我们的加密风筝NFT
We launch our
crypto kite
NFTs next month.
基督风筝NFT
So the Crimson Crypto Club
所以如果加密风筝能行的话
could have a lot
of money to invest
就会有很多钱可以投资
if the crypto
kites fly.
又是那该死的风筝
RANDAL: Again
with the fucking kites.
伙计们 我们需要搞点钱来制作一部真正的电影
Guys, we need real loot
to make a real movie,
而不是你们假装黑客帝国的钱
和你们他妈的风筝钱
not your make pretend
Matrix money,
you fuckin'
kite fucker.
我厌倦了这里扼杀风筝的态度
I'm sick and tired
of the kite killing
attitude around here.
(SCOFFING)
(DOOR OPENS)
不管怎么说 回到预算
RANDAL: Anyway,
back to the budget.
如果我们把店拿去抵押贷款怎么样？
What if we took
out a loan
against the store?
贷款？为什么我们不先退一步
A loan?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Why don't we just
先考虑一下这个问题？
slow down a minute
and think about
this first?
退一步？我差点就死了 伙计
Slow down?
I almost died, man.
不能再拖了
It doesn't get
any slower than that.
我不想再那样了
I'm not getting all
"Dante" about this.
那是什么意思？
Uh, what's that
supposed to mean?
你是那种永远无法决定是拉屎还是下锅的人
You're the guy
who can never decide
whether to shit
or get off the pot.
好吧 我时间不多了
Well, I don't
have time
for that anymore.
从现在开始 我要赚大钱
要不然在这里有什么意义？
From now on,
I'm gonna shit bricks
or what's the point
of being here?
所以 来吧 伙计 当一次我的后盾 就在我身后
So, come on, man,
get behind me
when I shit for once.
所以我可以做什么 替你擦屁股？
So I can what,
wipe your ass?
(SCOFFS)
你知道的 我也不想这样
You know, I don't wanna get
all "Dante" about this,
但是找别人来收拾你的残局吧
but find someone else
to take your shit.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(MELANCHOLY MUSIC PLAYING)
丽贝卡斯科特希克斯伯恩
生于1979 - 死于2006
好 他在这
BECKY: Well,
well, well,
here he is.
逃生艺术家
The escape artist.
我坐在你的坟墓上
I Sit on Your Grave.
(CHUCKLES) Didn't
we have that movie
at the video store?
影像店里不是有那部电影吗？
《我唾弃你的坟墓》
I Spit on Your Grave.
希克斯 你在梦里向我的坟墓吐口水
你最好起来道歉
Hicks, you spit
on my grave
in a dream,
you better wake up
and apologize.
Ah...
-所以这是一个梦
-如果是
So this is a dream.
Uh, if it is,
那么你需要学会有更大的梦想
then you need to learn
to dream bigger.
我的意思是 真的吗
这是你能做的最好的吗？
I mean, really,
this is the best
that you can do?
墓地？
A cemetery?
你不能梦到我们发生关系
You can't dream
us into sex...
在夏威夷
on the beach...
的沙滩上？
in Hawaii?
说得像你现在想和我发生性关系一样
Like you'd wanna
have sex with me now.
我是个老男人
(GROANS)
I'm an old man.
我会让你知道死亡只会增加你的性欲
I'll have you know
that being dead only
increases your
sex drive.
(LAUGHS)
死人活着就是为了发生关系
The dead live
to fuck.
-所以你死后会做爱吗？
-那当然
So you have sex
in the afterlife?
Hell's yeah.
在天堂里除了做爱别无他法
There's nothing to do
in Heaven except fuck.
(SCOFFS)
That's what
makes it Heaven.
这就是使它成为天堂的原因
我不敢相信我妻子和死人发生性关系
I can't believe my
wife's having sex
with dead people.
著名的死者 我现在在名人巡回赛上
Famous dead people.
I'm on the celebrity
circuit now.
吹牛 说出一个你在天堂操过的名人
Bullshit. Name one
famous person you
fucked in Heaven.
一个 好的
One. Okay.
(SMACKS LIPS)
先生 我已经和克利奥帕特拉的鬼魂缠绵过了
I have knocked boots
with the ghost
of Cleopatra, sir.
还有迈尔斯戴维斯
Oh.
And Miles Davis
和弗雷德里克道格拉斯一起
and Frederick
Douglass,
together.
-乔治华盛顿
-什么？
George Washington...
What?
卡佛
Carver.
Oh.
你知道我有多爱花生酱
You know how much
I love peanut butter.
-是的
-还有谁？
True.
Who else?
卡尔萨根
Um, Carl Sagan.
Oh!
A real thinker.
一个真正的思想家
Um...
马尔科姆艾克斯
Malcolm X.
-马尔科姆艾克斯
-冷静点
Malcolm triple X.
Oh, settle down.
而且我敢肯定你对他们都放得很开
And I'm sure you're letting
them all go ass to mouth.
是的 他们很有名
Uh, yeah,
they're famous.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
你认为我想要这个 不是吗？
You think
I want this,
don't you?
你对我有意思？
You carrying
the torch for me?
我告诉过你我对浪漫爱情的感受 希克斯
I told you how
I feel about
romantic love, Hicks.
我记得
Oh, I remember.
你很有说服力
You were very
convincing.
Mmm.
直到我求婚的那一天
Right up until the day
I proposed.
我们只认识了大概15分钟
We only knew each other
for, like, 15 minutes.
而你这15年都在为我哀悼
You've been mourning me
for, like, 15 years.
那你想让我怎么做？你想让我忘记你？
So what do you
want me to do?
You want me to just
forget about you?
你是我梦寐以求的一切
You were all
I ever dreamed about.
你们俩
Both of you.
(BECKY SIGHS)
(TEARFULLY) Now...
现在
天啊 我好孤独
God, I'm so alone.
(CRYING)
我知道
(SOFTLY) I know.
我知道失去我和格蕾丝
I know losing me
and Grace...
伤透了你的心
broke you.
但你不知道你有多幸运
But you don't know
how lucky you have it.
什么？
What?
我们的生命已经结束了
The Book of Life
is closed
for the two of us.
但是你
But you... can still
turn a page.
仍然可以翻篇
你可以继续写你的人生故事
You get to keep writing
the story of your life.
没有你还有什么意义？
Why bother without you?
因为还有更多的故事要讲 希克斯
Because there are
more tales
to tell, Hicks.
只要你还活着
As long as
you're alive,
你总能开始另一个篇章
you can always
start another chapter.
所以尽可能地活着
So live while you can,
love while you can.
尽你所能去爱
他妈的
God damn it.
大胆点
Dream bigger.
(SNIFFLES)
来自一个不相信浪漫爱情的女孩
That all sounds
pretty romantic
这一切听起来是多么的浪漫
coming from a girl
who doesn't believe
in romantic love.
我不相信浪漫的爱情
I don't believe
in romantic love.
这才是你
That's my girl.
但我确实相信你
But I do believe
in you.
(BECKY CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
想要演电影吗？
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
到第一大道剧场试镜！
周日下午3点
第一大道剧场
我要感谢你们今天让我站在这里
Hey, I wanna thank
you guys for having
me here today.
我一直想成为一名演员
I've always wanted
to be an actor.
很好
Nice.
我今天甚至都不应该在这里！
I'm not even
supposed to be
here today!
我今天甚至都不应该在这里
I'm not even supposed
to be here today.
我今天甚至都不应该在这里
I'm not even supposed
to be here today.
我今天甚至都不应该在这里
I'm not even supposed
to be here today.
(SOBBING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
我今天甚至都不应该在这里
(STRAINED) I'm not even
supposed to be here today.
我他妈的今天甚至都不应该他妈的在这里
你们这些混蛋
I'm not even supposed
to fucking be here
to fucking day, fucks.
Oh, shit! I thought
that was the police.
该死！我还以为是警察
我今天甚至都不应该在这里
I'm not even supposed
to be here.
借助灰颅的力量
By the power
of Grayskull,
我今天甚至都不应该在这里！
I am not supposed
to be here today!
嘿 我是乔
Hey, I'm Joe.
我今年45岁 刚离婚
然后我想来这里试试
Uh, I'm 45-years-old,
recently divorced,
and I figured I'd give
this shit a go. Uh...
我今天甚至都不应该在这里
I am not even supposed
to be here today.
去他妈的
Damn right.
Uh... (HUMMING)
狮子脸
Lion face. (ROARS)
柠檬脸
Lemon face. (GRUNTING)
我今天甚至都不应该在这里
I'm not even supposed
to be here today.
介绍一下我自己
Um... (CLEARS THROAT)
A little about me.
业内称我为波士顿约翰
I'm known professionally
as Boston John.
那是个笔名
That's a nom de plume.
Uh, Robert De Niro
is my fuckin'...
Lone star.
罗伯特德尼罗是我他妈的孤星
你知道我在说什么吗？
闭上你的眼睛 就
You know what I'm saying?
Close your eyes. Just...
闭上眼睛 听着 准备好了吗？好了吗？
Close your eyes.
Just listen.
Ready? All right?
我有乳头 格雷格
(MIMICKING ROBERT DE NIRO)
I have nipples, Greg.
你能给我挤奶吗？
Could you milk me?
那是一个 婊子 一整天
Fuck, that is one,
bitch. All day.
你能给我一个像施瓦辛格这样的吗？
Can you give me one
like Schwarzenegger?
我今天甚至都不应该在这里
(MIMICS ARNOLD)
I'm not even supposed
to be here today.
但是你能帕西诺一点吗？
But can you, uh,
Pacino that shit?
(MIMICS AL PACINO)
Ooh-ah!
什么时候 主？
(SHOUTS) When, Lord?
我什么时候才能看到该死的帆船？
When will I see
the God damn sailboat?
那是我自己内心深处的想法
That came from a real
deep personal place.
我有一个博鳌亚洲论坛
I have a BFA.
我是一名有戏剧背景的演员
Uh, I'm a theater
background actor.
作为一名有戏剧背景的演员
我在纽约接受了培训
As an actor with
a theater background,
I was classically
trained in New York.
你有考虑过用这个来做音乐剧吗？
Have you
actually thought
因为它可能是
about going
musical with this?
'Cause it could be...
我今天甚至
♪ I'm not even...
都不应该
Supposed to be here.
在这里
♪ Today ♪
Hah, hoo, hah.
Yeah-cha!
换脚踢 两下响指 爵士手
Kick ball change
and snap,
snap, jazz hands.
那很不错 伙计
That is beautiful, man.
小弗雷迪普林兹
Freddie Prinze Jr.
“我会操任何会动的东西”
"I'll fuck anything
that moves."
等等 伙计 这是色情片吗？
Wait, wait a minute, man,
is this a porno?
我会操任何会动的东西
I'll fuck anything
that moves.
-我会操任何会动的东西
I'll fuck anything
that moves.
这有点露骨 让我这样试一下吧 等等
That's a little bit
in your face.
Let me try it
like this, hold on.
我可以借你的内裤 用大约十分钟吗？
Can I borrow
your underpants
for about ten minutes?
我会操任何会动的东西
I'll fuck anything
that moves.
还有 傻子
And, fool,
我总是带着砍刀
I always carry
a machete.
我会操任何会动的东西！
I'll fuck anything
that moves!
听起来像我买大麻的那个人
Sounds like the guy
I buy weed from.
你知道这部电影需要什么吗？
You know what
this movie needs?
这些 这些疯子！
Deez. Deez nuts!
我可以给你一个建议吗？
Can I just offer you
a piece of advice?
你知道这个剧本需要什么吗？
You know what
this script
needs right here?
就像一个在说脏话的老太太
Like an old lady
that says curse words.
天啊
Holy shit.
这垃圾剧本是谁写的？他的妈妈应该感到羞耻
Who wrote this garbage?
His mother should
be ashamed.
(INHALING)
他妈的？
The fuck?
他正在为《沉默的比尔》试镜
He's auditioning
for Silent Bill.
(SCOFFING)
不知道你知不知道《音乐之声》
I don't know if you know
Sound of Music,
那些木偶是其中最好的部分
the marionettes were
the best part of that.
我想这就是他们获得奥斯卡奖的原因
I think that's why
they won Oscars.
是不是值得考虑
It's worth
thinking about
也许能用木偶来做整部电影？
maybe doing
the whole movie
with marionettes.
(ROCK MUSIC FADES)
该吃药了 铁皮人
Take your
heart pills,
Tin Man.
嘿
Hey.
所以 融资情况如何？
So, how's it going
with the financing?
你给我筹钱了没？
You raise
my money, yet?
如果是你的钱
If it's your money,
-那为什么是我来筹？
-那是好莱坞
then how come
I have to raise it?
That's Hollywood.
(CHUCKLES)
-你读完剧本了吗？
-昨晚看完了
Did you finish
reading the script?
Last night.
然后呢？很有趣 对吧？
And? It's funny,
right?
是很有趣
It's funny,
但这就像我的整个人生在我眼前闪现
but it was like
my entire life flashed
before my eyes.
我的人生在你眼前一闪而过
My life flashed
before your eyes.
我很高兴你还是保留了一些东西
I was glad you left
some stuff out.
所以
So, uh...
这些家伙中的哪一个可以扮演我？
which one of these guys
gets to play me?
这些男生都太年轻
Well, the guys
are too young
and hot to play you.
What the fuck?
-太帅了 演不了你
-他妈的什么？
而且没有人像我这么风趣
And nobody's nearly
funny enough to play me.
那么 你打算怎么办？
So then,
what are you gonna do?
我要自己扮演我的角色
I'm gonna play
my part myself.
(ROCK MUSIC CONTINUES)
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS)
好了 我们要关门了
All right, already,
we're closing.
Gee whiz!
为什么？你太冒犯我了！
Why? You're highly
offending me!
是的 耶稣
Yeah, yeah,
yeah. Jesus.
对不起 女士 我们已经关门了
I'm sorry, ma'am,
we're closed.
是我 兰德尔
It's me, Randal.
Huh. Cool.
Blade Runner,
I like that.
酷 《银翼杀手》 我喜欢这样
谢谢 什么是《银翼杀手》？
Thanks. What's
a Blade Runner?
虽然你以前从未演过或导演过电影
Can we get back to you
acting in a movie
我们能否再探讨一下
that you're directing
even though you've
never acted in
您要自导自演电影这件事？
or directed
a movie before?
它适用于奥森威尔斯
It worked for
Orson Welles.
你不是个演员
(SIGHS) You're not
an actor.
霍华德斯特恩也不是 但他在电影中
扮演了关于他的生活的角色
Neither was
Howard Stern,
but he acted
in the movie
about his life.
如果你把它称之为表演的话
(SCOFFS) If you
call that acting.
你认为你可以做得更好吗？
You think you
can do better?
比在私处里的霍华德斯特恩迪德更好？
Better than Howard Stern
did in Private Parts?
这不是一个高标准
(CHUCKLES)
It's not a high bar.
太好了 因为你在扮演的是丹T
Great, because
you're playing Dan-T.
什么？不不不 我不是 我演不了
What? No, no, no.
I'm not. I can't act.
你和我们在试镜时看到的任何一个小丑一样好
You're as good
as any of the jokers
we saw at
1the audition.
此外 如果我要扮演我 那你就得扮演你
Besides, if I'm
gonna play me,
you gotta play you.
你必须这样做 丹T先生
You have
to do this,
Mr. Dan-T.
看在上帝的份上吧 请不要再叫我丹T先生了
DANTE: Oh,
for God's sakes,
please stop calling me
Mr. Dan-T.
那是另一回事 去他妈的所有假名字
That's another thing.
Fuck all the fake names.
这是什么东西 《疯狂杂志》？
What is this shit,
Mad Magazine?
兰德尔正在扮演兰德尔
Randal is
playing Randal.
但丁在扮演但丁 又名但丁先生
Dante is playing Dante,
aka Mr. Dante,
埃利亚斯在扮演埃利亚斯
and Elias is
playing Elias.
我也在电影里？
ELIAS: I'm in
the movie, too?
是的 作为一个撒旦教徒扮演基督徒
Yup. And as a Satanist
playing a Christian,
你的戏份最多
you've gotta
act the most.
这是我自己
It's my very
own chance...
转变的机会
to transform.
并且改变你 大黄蜂
And transform
you shall,
Bumblebee.
一旦但丁先生获得了他妈的资金
Soon as Mr. Dante
secures our
fuckin' financing.
Yo, it's too bad
you didn't marry
that Emma chick,
可惜你没有娶那个艾玛小妞
那个有大阴蒂的
the one with
the big clit.
她不是洗车店的女继承人之类的吗？
Wasn't she like some
kinda car wash heiress
or something?
你能集中注意力吗？
DANTE: Can you focus?
即使我们自己演
Even if we do
play ourselves,
你还是需要给所有客户的角色选角
you still got to cast
all the customer parts.
为什么我每天都已经
Why am I casting
customers to say
all this stupid shit
在看那些顾客说蠢话了
when I still see
the real customers
who said all
the stupid shit
in the first place
还要找人扮演说这些蠢话的顾客
come in here every day?
They can do it.
他们就可以做到
Oh, my God,
you can't just turn
我的上帝 你不能把普通人变成电影明星
regular people
into movie stars.
Noinch, noinch, noinch!
Smokin' weed.
吸大麻
吸大麻！
Smokin' weed!
来包烟 兄弟
Pack of wraps,
my good man.
是时候放松一下 喝点啤酒 抽点大麻
Time to kick back,
drink some beers
and smoke some weed.
你拥有一整个的烟草店
You own a whole
weed store.
嘿 兰德尔 我有个主意
Hey, Randal,
I've got an idea.
如果杰和鲍勃扮演杰和鲍勃怎么样？
What if Jay and Bob
play Jay and Bob?
好吧 我们可以问他们
Well, we can
ask 'em. Yo.
你们想出演我的电影吗？
Youse guys want to
be in my movie?
Ooh, a pornography
movie?
色情电影？
RANDAL: It's not
a porno movie.
这不是色情电影
是我们在你店里拍摄的电影
It's the movie
we're shooting
in your store.
那部电影？你还没弄完？
(SCOFFS) That movie?
You still ain't done?
我们甚至还没有开始
We haven't even
started yet.
我不知道 我们会在电影中扮演谁？
I don't know. Who would
we be playing
in this movie?
有两个角色是我按照
Well, it's these
two characters
I kind of based
你和玛吉辛普森为原型创作出来的
on you
and Maggie
Simpson here.
看看你的第一个场景
Check out your
first scene.
这些人不是真正的演员
DANTE: These guys
aren't real actors.
但他们是真混蛋 这也是我想要的
But they are real
fucked up and I could
work with that.
这听起来一点也不像我
This doesn't sound
like me at all.
你在说什么？
What are you
talking about?
里面所有的对话都是我亲耳听到
你在这里所说过的东西
All the shit in there
is all the stuff
I've personally heard
you say around here.
我才不会这样说话 伙计
I do not talk
like this, man.
为什么这里的我会说这些蠢话
Why do you have me
saying stupid shit like
-一直说“斯努奇布奇“？
-要不然这样
"Snootchie Bootchies"
all the time?
RANDAL: I'll tell
you what.
如果你们在电影中扮演自己的话
If you guys
play yourselves
in the movie,
我也会让你们负责伙食区
I'll let you guys
be in charge
of Crafty, too.
那么伙食区是什么呢？
So what's
Crafty about?
除了在电影中扮演喜剧角色
Well, in addition to
being the comic
relief in the movie,
你们还将负责剧组里所有的伙食
you'd also be in charge
of all the food on set.
Ooh, we learned
about food prep
以前我们自己开餐厅时
我们学会了食物准备
back when we ran
the fucking Cock Smoker.
那里不就是你们分毒品的地方吗？
Wasn't that place
just a drug front?
(CHUCKLING) No,
we had drugs
in the front
不 我们两边都有
and drugs
in the back.
所以如果埃利亚斯扮演的是自己
而这些混蛋也扮演他们自己
DANTE: So if Elias
is playing Elias
and these dopes
are playing themselves,
你打算找谁来演维罗妮卡？
who are you gonna get
to play Veronica?
你怎么不早点问呢
Well, funny you
should ask,
'cause earlier today
I sent the script
我刚刚把剧本发给一个
to someone who
will be absolutely...
(CLICKS TONGUE)
...perfect to
play Veronica.
我觉得非常适合演维罗妮卡的人
(DOOR OPENS)
你他妈的以为你是谁？
Who the fuck
do you people
think you are?
-维罗妮卡？
-这是什么脏东西？
Veronica?
What is this filth?
这是什么让我成为一个又放荡
What is this gamey,
tawdry trash
又俗气的垃圾？
that makes me out to be
some slutty sex maniac?
这只是一部我正在制作的关于我的生活的电影
RANDAL: It's just
a movie I'm making
about my life,
and I thought
然后我认为你在里面扮演自己会很有趣
it'd be fun for you
to play yourself in it.
是吗？
Oh, you did?
对啊
Yeah.
-那你是他妈的有病了！
-嘿！
Then you are
fucking sick!
Hey!
以我的艺术表达来看它
Watch it with
my artistic expression.
“艺术表达”？这就是我的生活
"Artistic expression"?
That's my life.
这是我的生活
It's my life.
好了 大家冷静一下
Okay, everybody,
calm down.
Jeez.
你要是在大学里学电影的话肯定会被追杀的
DANTE: Oh, come on,
you would have killed
to have been
in a film in college.
-你主修戏剧
-我辅修戏剧
You majored
in drama.
I minored
我主修口腔外科
I majored in
oral surgery.
所有人都欢呼口腔女王
All hail the queen
of oral.
-去你的
-外科女王
Fuck you.
Surgery.
你没有让我说完
You didn't
let me finish.
我也不会让你拍完这部电影的
And I'm not gonna let you
finish this film either,
除非你把我的角色去掉
not with me
as a character.
我不是你在你肮脏的无脑电影中讲的他妈的笑话
I'm not some
fucking joke
you get to tell
in your dirty
little B movie,
你这两个无脑的索德伯格
you two-bit
strip mall Soderbergh.
我认为自己更像是理查德林克莱特
I see myself
more like retail's
Richard Linklater.
你想这样做吗？
VERONICA: You want
to do this?
也行 把我的角色拿掉
Fine, but leave
me out of it.
不像你们两个 我有一份稳定的工作
Unlike either of you,
I've got a grown-up job.
不像你们两个 我有一个家庭
And unlike either of you,
I've got a family.
那个 我很抱歉
Oh, man,
I'm so sorry.
我 对不起
I... Sorry.
(SOBBING)
(DANTE SIGHS)
请不要哭泣
Please don't cry.
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
It's just been a shit day.
今天真不顺
(SOBBING)
我遇到了两件不幸的事
I had two
cancelations.
我的前任打电话告诉我
他不会把我们女儿的车
My ex calls
to tell me that
he's not putting
our daughter's car
列入他的保险
on his insurance,
所以现在不知怎的她在生我的气
and so now somehow
she's pissed at me.
然后我看到你说那些屁话
And then I see you
and say that shit.
没关系 真的
It's okay. Really.
我有点感觉 我觉得自己像是个混蛋
I kinda feel like...
I feel like such
an asshole.
嘿 罗尼
Hey, Ronnie.
(SNIFFLES)
如果兰德尔告诉我他要把剧本拿给你
If Randal told me he was
gonna send you the script,
我肯定会说不行的
I would've said no way.
但现在 我很高兴他那么做了
But now,
I'm glad he did.
因为
Because it's...
很高兴能见到你 即使在这种情况下
it's really nice to see you.
Even under the circumstances.
你看起来很棒
And you look great.
(SCOFFS)
你看起来比我年轻很多
You look way younger
than I do.
-是吗？
-是的
Yeah?
Yeah.
你觉得我看起来有多年轻？
How young you
think I look?
你看起来最多也
You don't look
a day over...
37.
(CHUCKLING)
所以
So, um...
(SMACKS LIPS)
你想要跟我发生关系吗？
You want to fuck?
(NO HOPE BY LOUSER PLAYING)
♪ I'm a mess
♪ All washed out
♪ Mostly regrets
♪ Laced with doubts
♪ All bruised up
(VERONICA AND DANTE MOANING)
♪ I'm knocked down
你认为这意味着维罗妮卡同意了吗？
You think
this means
Veronica is in?
我认为这意味着但丁肯定是
I think it means
Dante sure is.
♪ No hope
♪ No peace ♪
“沉默的鲍勃 你是个粗鲁的混蛋
但你可爱得要死”
JAY: "Silent Bob,
"you are a rude
motherfucker.
"But you are cute
as hell."
(CLEARING THROAT)
沉默的鲍勃！
(LOUDLY) Silent Bob!
你是个粗鲁的混蛋！
You are
a rrr-rude
motherfucker!
但是你可爱得要死！
But you're cute
as hell!
(ELIAS SNEEZING)
我把猫带来了 兰德尔
ELIAS: I brought
the cat, Randal.
完美 在我们准备好拍摄之前
Perfect. We don't
want him
going anywhere
我们不希望他靠近垃圾箱
near a litter box
until we're
ready to shoot.
所以你必须一整天抱着他
So you're gonna
have to hold
him all day.
但是我对猫过敏
But I'm allergic
to cats.
你必须为艺术牺牲 伙计
You got to suffer
for your art, man.
但这不是我的艺术 而是你的艺术
But it's not my art,
it's your art.
你不应该是受苦的那个人吗？
Shouldn't you be
the one doing
the suffering?
我差点死于心脏病发作时 还没有受够吗？
I didn't
suffer enough
when I almost died
from a heart attack,
还要在这里受一下？
which I might
add was after
a heated exchange
about kites?
我的过敏症使我对你的情感勒索免疫
My allergies
have made me immune
to your emotional
blackmail.
(DOOR OPENS)
(CAT PURRING)
看看他的演技
Check out
this acting.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Silent Bob,
沉默的鲍勃 你是个粗鲁的混蛋！
you are a rrr-rude
motherfucker!
但是你可爱得要死
But you're cute
as hell.
很自然 很微妙 我喜欢
Very natural,
and subtle.
I like it.
那么 你今天感觉如何？
So, how are you
feeling today?
你知道吗 我感觉就像
那个在影像店打工的孩子
Oh, you know,
I feel like that kid
that worked
in the video store,
对电影的语言完全熟悉
fully fluent in
the language of cinema.
就像我天生就是导演一样
It's like I was born
to direct.
不 兄弟 我的意思是 你上个月心脏病发作了
No, bro. I mean,
you had a heart
attack last month.
那 不 我感觉很好
Oh, that.
No, I feel fine.
昨晚在车上过了一夜之后
How do you
feel today
今天感觉如何？
after your Range Rover
sleepover last night?
-别说
-当我说要当制片人的时候
Stop it.
When I said
to be a producer,
我不是说老来得子那一说
I didn't mean produce
a late-in-life child.
不情愿的制作人
Unwilling producer.
我也没有申请做这份工作 但我还是做了
I didn't ask
for this job,
but I am doing it.
所以我今天有一个关于资金的会议
So I have a meeting
today about money.
他妈的行啊
Fucking A,
that's producing, J.J.
我还给你找了个电影摄影师
And I found you
a cinematographer.
-什么？
-我可以为你介绍吗
What?
May I present to you...
摄影师鲍勃
Shooter Bob.
沉默的鲍勃会成为我们的摄影师吗？
Silent Bob is
gonna be our DP?
妈的 太棒了 我们都要做DP！
Shit, yeah,
we all gonna be
doing DPs!
DP是名称
Uh, DP is the name
of the job.
你说是摄影师
You said
it was cinematographer.
摄影师就是DP
The cinematographer
is the DP.
伙计 不要表现得像你知道所有行业的俚语一样
Man, don't be
acting like
you know
all the industry
slang and shit.
我和沉默的鲍勃是这里唯一
Me and Silent Bob
are the only ones here
去过电影拍摄片场的人 两次
who've actually been
on a movie set. Twice.
(RANDAL SCOFFS)
来吧
RANDAL: Come on.
是的 他是一个非常规的选择
Yes, he's an
unconventional choice,
但你是一个非常规的电影制作人
but you are an
unconventional
filmmaker making
-要拍一部非常规的电影
-是的
an unconventional film.
Yeah.
你要我把我一生的故事
You want me to entrust
the story of my life
to the Quiet Place.
托付到寂静之地
他的Instagram上有一些非常漂亮的照片
He has some
really nice shots
on his Instagram.
(SCOFFS)
来吧 给他一个机会 伙计
Come on, give him
a chance, man.
也许他会和你说同样的电影语言
Maybe he speaks
the language of
cinema like you do.
这家伙从不说
The guy never
speaks at all.
好的 我们刚看过这里侦察 颜色真难看
Okay, so we just
scouted in here,
and the colors
are fucking ugly.
所以沉默鲍勃想把整部电影
So Silent Bob wants to
shoot the whole movie
拍成黑白的
in black and white.
《辛德勒的名单》是黑白电影吗？
Schindler's List
black and white?
What, is he nuts?
什么 他疯了吗？
不 我是他妈的电影制片人
Uh, no,
I'm a fucking
filmmaker.
任何称职的电影制作人都会知道
And any filmmaker
worth their salt
would know
that the colors
这个地方的颜色真他妈的可怕
in this place
are fucking ghastly.
处理它们的唯一方法就是
The only way
you could
deal with them
通过黑白来进行中和
is to neutralize
them by going in
black and white,
这也可以作为
which will also
kind of act as
a commentary
对商业无灵魂本质的评论
on the soulless
nature of commerce
同时在潜意识里让观众觉得
while subliminally
giving the audience
the impression
他们正在通过假想商店的
that they're watching
our heroes
安全摄像头观看我们的主角的生活
from the perspective
of an imaginary
store security cam.
我就是这么想的
That's what
I was thinking.
Mmm-hmm.
-这就是艺术家的想法
-是的
That's what
an artist thinks.
Yup.
但是 你知道 这取决于你
But, you know,
it's up to you.
不过 如果不让我拍黑白的话
However,
I'm shooting it
in black and white,
我他妈的就不拍了
or I ain't shooting
it at all,
motherfucker.
没错
That's right.
(EXHALES)
(LINE RINGING)
天哪 他看起来很胖
Jesus, he looks fat.
你没有静音 艾玛
You're not
on mute, Emma.
我知道 所以呢？你好
I know. So? Hello.
你好
Hi, you.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
佛罗里达怎么样？
How's Florida?
到处都是混蛋 但至少不是泽西岛
Full of assholes,
but at least
it's not Jersey.
你想要什么 但丁？
What do you
want, Dante?
好吧 这会从左场出来
Okay, uh, this is gonna
come out of left field,
但是 我希望我能借点钱
but, um, I was hoping
I could borrow some money.
-他妈的不行
-这不给我的 是给兰德尔的
Fuck no.
It's not for me.
It's for Randal.
哦 那更他妈的不行
Oh, then double fuck no.
他心脏病发了 艾玛
He had a heart
attack, Emma.
好的 我希望他死了
Good. I hope
he dropped dead.
他没有
He didn't.
所以他需要钱
So he needs
the money for, uh...
来付医院的账单
for the hospital bills.
兰德尔没有任何保险
Randal doesn't have
any insurance.
所以他妈的什么？
So the fuck what?
即使我想帮忙 但是我真不想
Even if I wanted to help,
which I don't,
我不会给兰德尔任何免费的钱
I'm not giving
Randal Graves
any free money.
艾玛 拜托
Emma, please.
你和我曾经承诺 如果我们需要帮助
You and I once
promised that if
we ever needed help,
无论发生什么 我们都会一直帮助对方的
we'd always be there
for each other,
no matter what.
那是在你欺骗我之前
That was before
you cheated on me
at a fucking
donkey show.
再见了 但丁！
Goodbye, Dante!
不 等等
No, no.
Wait, wait, wait.
(GROANS)
拜托了 艾玛
Please, Emma.
我真的很绝望
I'm desperate here.
你有抵押品吗？
Do you even have
any collateral?
如果必须这样的话
If I have to...
我可以签署我一半的店作为抵押品
I can sign over my
half of the QuickStop
as collateral.
那个垃圾？
That shithole? Ugh.
-这是怎么回事？
-我们在拍电影
What's all this about?
We're making a movie.
不是吧 色情电影？
No shit.
A pornography movie?
-这需要多长时间？
-21晚
How long does
that take?
Twenty-one nights.
我的导演朋友要在这里呆上21个晚上
It's gonna take
my auteur friend
here 21 nights
让他在电影中吃自己的鸡巴
for him to cinematically
suck his own dick.
连续？
In a row?
《便利》我不明白
"In Convenience."
I don't get it.
第十场 第一条！
Scene ten,
take one!
(OPERATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
猫牧人！
Cat Wrangler!
(BULLHORN FEEDBACK)
(ELIAS WHEEZING)
(BODY THUDS)
(WHEEZING)
好了 我们准备
All right,
let's go.
来
And...
开始
action.
天啊
Holy shit.
拉屎了
We got poop.
开始
And action.
(BULLHORN FEEDBACK)
他妈的
Fuck.
(OPERATIC MUSIC CONTINUES)
(IMPERCEPTIBLE)
你还在等什么？跳舞啊！
What are you
waitin' for?
Dance!
我不会在所有这些该死的人的注视下跳舞
I ain't doing this
with all these fuckin'
people watching.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
停！
(BULLHORN FEEDBACK)
Cut!
人才真是个小婊砸
(SIGHS) The talent's
being a little bitch.
你们可以在店里等吗？
Can you guys wait
in the video store?
我会开机
I'll run the camera.
难以置信 真的吗？
DANTE: Unbelievable.
Really?
这样 行了吧？我把人都清了
There, ya happy?
I cleared the set.
他妈的跳舞 伙计
So fucking
dance, man.
你他妈的跳舞
You fucking dance.
-婊子
-准备
Bitch.
RANDAL: And...
开始
action.
什么鬼 乔乔西瓦？
What the fuck,
JoJo Siwa?
看看这该死的家伙看着我们！
Look at this
fucking guy
looking at us!
他甚至都没有注意
He's not even paying
attention. Gee whiz.
你也得进去 笨蛋
You have to go
inside, too, cuck.
那谁他妈来开拍？
Who the fuck's
gonna run the camera?
按下按钮 然后走开
Push the button
and walk away.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
(CAMERA BEEPS)
All right.
好吧
开始
(BULLHORN FEEDBACK)
Action.
我猜
I guess.
(FIND YOUR WAY BACK  BY
JEFFERSON STARSHIP PLAYING)
♪ You know, it's been
A long, long road
♪ Since I packed up and left
On my own...
好的 现在 抓着柜台
All right, now,
hold on to
the counter.
我会拉 好吗？开始了
I'm going
to pull, okay?
Here we go.
Ah...
♪ Just trying
To get back to her heart
开始
(GRUNTS)
Action.
RST影视公司
我们需要一些胸和屁股 耶！
We need some tits
and ass, yeah!
♪ I sure ain't got no home...
停！
And cut.
Ha-ha. (GRUNTS)
(WHISTLES)
干得好 干得漂亮
Nice job,
nice work.
Um...
好吧 我们正朝这扇门再来一次
All right,
we're doing
the same shot
just over to
this door.
声音要在这里 让我们把棍子拿到那里
...sound here.
Let's get the
sticks over there.
埃利亚斯 你听着吗？
Elias, you with us?
好的 我们正在做同样的事情
Okay, we're doing
the same thing.
我们只是 有点 过来这里
We're just, kind of,
coming over here.
We're gonna stay
on the same...
我们要保持原样
♪ Find your way back... ♪
准备 开始
And... action.
你知道 世界上有数百万罚单 伙计
You know, there are
a million fines
in the world, dude.
“数百万罚款”？什么鬼 伙计？
RANDAL: "Millions
of fines"?
What the hell, man?
不是这句
That's not
the line.
“世界上有一百万个”
"There's a million
fine-looking women
“漂亮的女人 伙计”
"in the world,
dude."
在这个世界后还有十亿个 伙计！
There are a billion
behinds in this
world, dude!
Whoo!
Not "billions
of behinds."
不是“后还有十亿个”
“一百万个漂亮的女人”
"A million
fine-looking
women."
你知道 他们也在杀猪 伙计
You know, they're
killing swines
in the world, dude.
操他妈的 你这个没演技的混蛋！
Jesus fucking Christ,
you non-acting fuck!
我自己来
I will do it myself.
Ahem!
你知道这世上有一百万个
You know,
there's a million
fine-looking women
漂亮的女人 伙计
in the world, dude,
但她们并不都在工作中带给你烤宽面条
but they don't
all bring you
lasagna at work.
她们大多数人只会给你戴绿帽
Most of them
just cheat on you.
-你都在说晚上那档事
-嗯？
You All About
Eve -ining fuck.
Well?
系好安全带 这将是一个颠簸的夜晚
Fasten your seatbelts.
It's gonna be
a bumpy night.
就是这样 他不再爱你了
RANDAL: So that's it.
He doesn't love
you anymore.
他爱的是凯特琳
He loves Caitlin.
-他告诉了你这一切？
-差不多吧
And he told
you all this?
Pretty much.
除了潜在的同性恋但是
All except the latent
homosexuality but...
什么鬼 伙计？
What the fuck,
man?
我们在这里拍电影
We're making
a movie here. Ew!
这与我的表弟沃尔特的死相比根本不值一提
RANDAL: It's nothing
compared to how
my cousin Walter died.
-他是怎么死的？
-他的脖子断了
DANTE: How'd he die?
RANDAL: He broke his neck.
这很尴尬？
That's embarrassing?
他在试图吃自己的鸡巴时扭断了脖子
He broke his neck
trying to suck
his own dick.
天哪 伙计
JAY: Holy shit, man.
-你说的是真的吗？
-你疯了吗？
Is that shit true?
RANDAL: Are you nuts?
他妈的闭嘴
Shut the fuck up.
我们正在拍摄
We're shooting
a scene here.
(FIND YOUR WAY BACK  CONTINUE)
♪ I know it's too late now
请把钱留在柜台上 需要找零钱时才拿
诚实一点
♪ But I wish I could
Go back in time
♪ And start all over somehow
♪ And get it right
From the start
♪ Find your way back
To her heart
♪ Find your way back ♪
Uh, what the
hell is this?
这到底是什么？
这个故事需要一点动作戏
所以我在最后添加了
The story needs
a little action
so I added a scene
where Cohee
科希进来抢劫这个地方的场景
comes in to
rob the place
at the end.
在这个过程中 你会被枪杀
And in the process,
you get shot.
没门 我不会让你在第三幕之后就把我杀了
No way. I'm not letting
you kill me off
in the third act.
如果有续集呢？
What if there's
a sequel?
续集？我是什么？黑客？
A sequel?
What am I? A hack?
科希 制片人说我要剪掉你的场景呢
Cohee, producer
says I gotta cut
your scene, man.
我还是能收钱 对吧？
Yo, I'm still pay
or play, right?
宣传？是不是有点早了？
Publicity? Isn't it
a little early for that?
我一生都在看报纸
然而我唯一一次在报纸上看到我的名字
I've been
reading the paper
my whole life
and the only time
I've seen my name in it
是在头条下
“当地的杂货店店员有严重的心脏病”
was under
the headline,
"Local grocer has
massive heart attack."
所以我想你以制片人的官方身份
So I thought in your
official capacity
as producer,
也许你可以找个小记者来这里
maybe you can get
a cub reporter
over here
写一篇关于你的导演电影的报道
to do a story
about your director
in action.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
“我向你保证 我们在营业”
JAY: "I assure you
we're open."
我不明白
I don't get it.
有些野蛮的人总是把口香糖粘在锁里
Some savages are
always sticking
gum in the locks,
所以我把它写进了剧本
so I wrote it
into the script
to be the reason
作为休业的原因
the shutters
are closed all day.
这样 我们可以在晚上拍摄并假装是白天
That way,
we can shoot
at night
and pretend
it's day out.
我他妈的真讨厌好莱坞这么假
I fucking hate
how fake
Hollywood is.
我欣赏不来你的诡计 女士
RANDAL: I don't
appreciate
your ruse, ma'am.
-再说一次
-你的诡计
I beg your pardon.
Your ruse.
你狡猾的企图欺骗我
Your cunning attempt
to trick me.
这是我最后一次在这里租房！
This is the last
time I rent here!
会有人想念你的
You will be missed.
去你的！
Screw you!
你不能再在这里租房了！
You're not
allowed to rent
here anymore!
好的！
JAY: Yeah!
停
RANDAL: And cut.
不错
(WOMAN EXHALES)
RANDAL: Nice work.
不错
Nice work.
好 现在给我十分钟 然后我就可以做我的了
Okay, now just give
me ten minutes
and then
I'll be ready
to do mine.
你的什么？
Your what?
Wah, Ricky!
瑞奇！
这是我最后一次在这里租房！
(CRYING) This is
the last time
I rent here!
(WAILING)
我不明白
I don't get it.
她想以露西再来一次
She wanted to do
one as Lucy.
《帝国反击战》的结局更好
Empire had
the better ending.
我的意思是 卢克被砍断了手
然后发现维德是他的父亲
I mean, Luke gets
his hand cut off,
finds out Vader's
his father.
汉被波巴费特冻住带走了
它以如此低调的一幕结束
Han gets frozen,
taken away by Boba Fett.
It ends on such
a down note.
-停
-什么？怎么了？
Cut.
What? What happened?
“汉被波巴费特冻住然后带走了”
RANDAL:
"Han gets frozen
"and taken away
by Boba Fett."
就是我说的
I said that.
不 你说 “汉被波巴费特冻住”
No, you said,
"Han gets frozen,
“带走了” 你漏掉了“然后”二字
"taken away
by Boba Fett."
You left out
the "and."
我现在进来吗 兰德尔？
Do I come in
now, Randal?
还没 托马斯 回去吧
Not yet, Thomas.
Go back out.
你可以责怪但丁在我的电影里即兴发挥
You can blame Dante
for ad-libbing
all over my movie
就像他是塞斯他妈的罗根一样
like he's Seth
fucking Rogan.
哦 我的上帝 我漏掉了一个词
Oh, my God,
I left out one word.
对于编剧来说 每一个字都是神圣的
Every word is sacred
to the writer.
这不是编剧
DANTE: This
isn't writing.
这是我生活中真实发生的一堆破事
It's a bunch of shit
that happened
for real in my life.
我的生活
My life.
我现在进来吗 兰德尔？
Do I come in
now, Randal?
还没 托马斯 回去吧
Not yet, Thomas.
Back.
伙计 托马斯又搞砸了？
Oh, man,
Thomas fucked
up again?
别他妈的搞事了 托马斯
Stop fucking
shit up, Thomas.
操 你对我父亲说了什么？
Hey, fuck-o.
What'd you say
to my father?
不如我操死你 你去他妈的混蛋！
How about I fuck
your shit up,
you fucking fuck
hole motherfucker!
射手鲍勃！
Shooter Bob!
那是我一生中听到或看到的最泽西的事情
That is the
Jersey-iest thing
I've ever heard
or seen in
my life. (LAUGHS)
开始
And action.
(SQUELCHES)
那是你的肺
That's your lung.
到这个时候 你的肺会看起来像这样
By this time,
your lung looks
like this.
那要不然你把香烟放回去 改试口香糖呢？
So why don't you put
the cigarettes back
and try some
gum instead?
来 口香糖 试试这个
Here, Chewlies gum,
try this.
天啊 好臭！
Oh, my God,
that reeks!
-天哪！
-那是什么？
God!
What is that?
我给你的肺模型怎么了？
What happened
to the model of
the lung I gave ya?
我是一个实物演员
I'm a method actor.
我为了在美食镇买的这个牛肚放弃了肺模型
I ditched
the model lung
for this tripe
I got at Foodtown.
-天啊
-我用我的舞台艺术能力
Jesus.
I used my power
of stagecraft
将胃视为肺 这就是实物
to see that
stomach as a lung.
It's method!
你是但丁希克斯
MAN: And you're
Dante Hicks.
我们去了同一所学校 你打曲棍球
We went to
the same school.
You played hockey.
是的 你怎么知道？
Yeah. How'd you
know that?
你还跟她出去吗？
You still going
out with her?
不 她要结婚了
No, she's
getting married.
-和你吗？
-不
To you?
No.
和一个亚洲设计专业的人
To an Asian
design major.
什么是...？你知道吗？
MAN: What is...
You know what?
停！我不能忍受这种种族歧视的东西
Cut, cut, cut!
I can't abide
by this racist shit.
种族歧视？这怎么就种族歧视了？
Racist? How the
hell is it racist?
看看这他妈缺乏多样性
Just look at all
this fucking
lack of diversity.
而且称一个人为亚洲设计专业的人
就感觉非常种族歧视
And calling some
guy an Asian
design major
just feels racist.
这不是种族歧视
That's not racist.
The guy literally
majored in Asian design.
这家伙确实主修亚洲设计
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
他不是一个亚洲的学生
并且还是设计专业的吗？
Wasn't he a, uh, Asian
student who was also
a design major?
他是一个热衷于亚洲设计的学生
He was a passionate
student of Asian design.
碰巧他自己也是个亚洲人
It just so happens
he himself was
coincidentally Asian.
(CASH REGISTER BEEPING)
放轻松一点老兄
Take it easy, man.
(CASH REGISTER BEEPS)
那么 我们要在哪里拍摄驴戏的场景呢？
So, uh, where are
we gonna shoot the
donkey show scene?
就在它发生地方 穆比餐厅
Where it happened.
Mooby's.
-我们的穆比？
-是的
Our Mooby's?
Yeah.
我们要怎么进去？
How are we supposed
to get in?
我让位置部门在处理了
I got the locations
department
working on it.
穆比 - 后门
从后面冲
EMPLOYEE: (GRUNTS)
It's stuck in my hair.
卡在我的头发里了
该死 你能搞出来吗？
Shit. Can you
get it?
Ugh. I hate wearing
the Mooby suit, man.
我讨厌穿穆比装 伙计
(SALLY WALK
BY IMINIKON PLAYING)
♪ I'm just trying to see
Miss Sally walk
♪ In a simple baddest
On the block
♪ I just wanna see
Miss Sally Double Dutch
Miss Sally fuck it up
♪ Fuck it up
♪ Eenie-meenie-miney-mo
♪ Yo girl say she tryna go
♪ Red light, green light
♪ Now you can't find yo ho
♪ Freeze tag, this froze
♪ Took her to the jewelry store
♪ Miss Sally walk
A-walkin' down the street
♪ Miss Sally walk...
来吧 兄弟们 我们走！
Come on, boys.
Let's go!
♪ I just wanna see
Miss Sally walk
♪ Miss Sally walk
A-walkin' down the street
(DONKEY BRAYING)
♪ I just wanna see
Miss Sally walk
Miss Sally walk ♪
穆比
(TRAIN HORN TOOTING)
不
No.
-不 什么？
-不 我不能进去
No what?
No, I... I can't
go inside.
你当然可以
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Of course, you can.
贝克斯 我不能
Becks, I can't.
我们在那个地方度过了我们一生中最美好的时光
We had the best
times of our lives
in that place.
直到我们中的一个生命结束
Until one of our
lives ended.
(SIGHS) It's just
a building, Hicks.
这只是一栋建筑 希克斯
这只是一栋我从那以后就没有进去过的建筑
It's just a building
I haven't been
inside since...
自从
(TEARFULLY) Since you...
我知道 对不起
I know. I'm sorry.
(WHIMPERING)
放下吧
Just turn the page.
你可以的 宝贝们
You can do this,
babes.
不
No. (WHIMPERING)
不要去
Don't go.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(SOFT MUSIC FADES)
(SIGHING)
Uh, Randal.
This is Lisa
兰德尔 这是丽莎和她的女儿
and her daughter...
Lisa.
丽莎
Uh, Lisa goes
to high school
丽莎曾经就读于亨利哈德逊地区高中
at Henry
Hudson Regional.
Oh.
这是我的丈夫兰多 他是可以直接下地狱的那个人
And this is my husband,
Lando, who can
go straight to hell.
我真生你的气
I'm so mad at you.
今天一整晚一句话都不要说
Don't say a damn word
the whole night.
连话都别想！
Don't even
think words!
RANDAL: Uh...
我们马上就要拍电影了
所以我得把你们赶出去
We're gonna shoot
a movie in a minute
so I gotta
chase you guys
out of here.
LISA: Oh, okay, my bad.
哦 好吧 我的错 我猜你的小视频
I guess you
don't want press
不需要新闻报道是吧
for your little
YouTube video, then.
你说的是新闻吗？
Did you say press?
但丁先生让他们来这里报道拍摄
ELIAS: Mr. Dante
asked them
to come here
to cover the shoot.
所以你说小丽莎是
So you're saying
little Lisa is...
Ah! High School Lisa.
高中丽莎
别叫她小丽莎 也最好别叫我大丽莎
Don't call her
little Lisa
and you better not
call me big Lisa.
高中丽莎为高中报纸写稿？
High School Lisa
writes for the high
school newspaper?
而她的父母是陪护
And her parents
are the chaperones.
真他妈棒
Fucking great.
即使一位父母今晚刚从脱衣舞俱乐部出来
LISA: Even though
one parent
just came out
of the strip club tonight
花掉了我在宾果游戏中仅得的5美元 婊子
spending all my $5 bills
that I got at bingo. Bitch.
嘿！制片人准备好了
Hey! The producer's
on set.
所以灯光！摄像！
So lights! Camera!
开始
Action! (CHUCKLES)
他看起来像是醉了
He looks drunk.
他看起来像是需要一块黄油和面包
He looks like
he needs a piece
of butter and bread.
这里面好冷
Ooh, it's cold in here.
会感冒咳嗽...喂！
Cough cold... Hey!
好的 你看
All right, look,
我意识到去穆比可能对你打击很大
I realize going to Mooby's
might have hit you hard
但你就这样逃走了吗？
but you just take off?
我们连驴戏都拍不出来！
We couldn't even shoot
the donkey show!
哦 大事
Oh, big deal.
你他妈怎么了 伙计？
What the fuck is wrong
with you, man?
试着想想自己以外的人
Try thinking of somebody
other than yourself for once.
-我自己？
-好的
Myself?
Okay.
我们需要拍摄这个场景
We're gonna
shoot this scene
因为高中报社的孩子
because the kid from
the high school newspaper
和她妈妈在等着
and her mom
are waiting.
感谢你理解那个任务
Thanks for understanding
the assignment on that one.
但是既然你今晚出现在这里之后就摆脸色
But since you
showed up here
shit-faced
今晚我们还没来得及开机就毁了
and ruined tonight
before we even had
a chance to roll,
我们明天要重新拍摄
we're gonna
re-shoot this tomorrow.
所以把你自私的屁股放在那个冷却器上
So get your selfish ass
out there on that cooler
让我们假装你真的对我的电影有帮助
and let's pretend
for a minute
you've actually
been helpful
on my movie,
这也是我要求你为我做的唯一一件事
which is, like,
the only thing
I ever asked you
to do for me
就在我差点死于该死的心脏病之后
and only after I almost
dropped dead
from a fucking
heart attack.
你真他妈难以置信 伙计
You're fucking
unbelievable, man.
快点！
Come on!
(DOOR OPENS)
(SIGHS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(WHISPERS) What...
便利
In Convenience.
愚蠢的名称
(SOFTLY) Stupid title.
第137场 第一条
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
Scene 137.
Take one.
他们是要拍成黑白电影吗？
Are they shooting this
in black and white?
我看到很多白色 我没有看到黑色
I see a lot of white.
I don't see the black.
开始
RANDAL: And action.
(MIMICKING JAWS THEME MUSIC)
♪ Da-dum, da-dum...
♪ Da-dum, da-dum, da-dum
♪ Da-dum, da-dum
Da-dum, dadum... ♪
莎莎鲨！
Salsa shark!
我们需要一艘更大的船
We're gonna need
a bigger boat.
人进笼子 笼子进莎莎酱
Man goes into cage,
cage goes into salsa.
鲨鱼在莎莎酱里 我们的鲨鱼
Shark's in the salsa.
Our shark.
什么？你怎么了 伙计？
Oh, what?
What's with you, man?
都20分钟了 你什么都没说
You haven't said
anything in,
like, 20 minutes.
你到底有什么问题？
What the hell's
your problem?
这一生
This life.
这一生？
This life?
我在休息日被困在这个坑里
I'm stuck in this pit
on my day off,
处理这个星球上的每一个混蛋
dealing with every backward
ass fuck on the planet.
我闻起来像鞋油
I smell like
shoe polish,
我的女朋友吃过36个鸡巴
and my girlfriend
sucked 36 dicks.
Thirty-seven.
LISA: Oh!
捂住耳朵 宝贝
Cover your ears,
baby girl.
他们为什么要这样说脏话？
Why the fuck
are they cursing
like that?
要么干活 要么走人
You need to shit
or get off the pot.
你他妈在说什么？
What the hell
are you talking about?
我说的是你的问题
I'm talking about
this thing you have,
这种无能为力去提高你的生活
this inability
to improve your
station in life.
-去你妈的
-是真的 伙计
Fuck you.
It's true, man.
你坐在那里责备生活给你带来的一切不如意
You sit there and
blame life for dealin'
ya a cruddy hand,
却没有一次去接受让你变成这样的勇气
never once
accepting
responsibility
for the way your
situation is.
你最好别管我 伙计
You better leave me
the fuck alone, man.
那是因为你过得很舒服 对吧？
It's because
you're comfortable,
right?
这对你来说就是最便利的生活方式
要是尝试改变它
This is the life of
convenience for you
and any attempt
to change it
would shatter
就会粉碎你为自己塑造的可悲的小世界
the pathetic microcosm
you've fashioned
for yourself.
什么？
What?
伙计 如果你不是这样一个该死的懦夫
Man, if you
weren't such
a fucking coward.
你他妈的能闭嘴吗？
(SHOUTS) Oh, would you
shut the fuck up?
不是这一句 伙计
That's not
the line, man.
-你在做什么？
-我的一生
What are you doing?
My whole life
你的嘴一直在以每小时一百万英里的速度跑着
you've been running
your mouth a million
miles an hour
而你却一言不发！
and saying
absolutely nothing!
(SCOFFS)
我得听你胡诌每个人和你所想的一切
I gotta listen
to you talk shit
about everybody
and everything
you think
好像世界都在等你来衡量！
as if the world's waiting
for you to weigh in!
他妈的没人在乎
Nobody fuckin' cares.
真不错啊
Oh, real nice, pal.
让我这么激动就因为我没死于
Get me all worked up
because it's not like
I had a heart attack
and almost...
心脏病！“我差点死于心脏病！”
Died! "I almost died
from a heart attack!
“我不是提过几千次了吗？”
"Did I not mention
that a couple of
thousand times yet?"
-操你妈
-“嘿 大家看看我”
Fuck you.
"Hey, everybody,
look at me.
“我就是那个活下来的人”
"I'm the boy who lived."
(LAUGHS SARCASTICALLY)
“所以我要拍一部电影”
"So I gotta
make a movie
“电影是关于我这个无情混蛋”
"all about what
a relentless fucking
asshole I am
“对我见过的每一个人来说 我很混蛋”
"to everybody
I ever met,
“尤其是我所谓的他妈的朋友”
"especially my so-called
fucking friends."
我们不再是朋友了 伙计
Oh, we're not friends
anymore, man.
你他妈可以相信这个
You can fucking
believe that shit.
-很好！
-是的
(LAUGHS) Oh, good!
Yeah.
因为如果我们不是朋友的话
Because if we're
not friends,
我就不必再担心这冰冷又残酷的事实
I don't have to worry
anymore what
the cold, hard truth
会对你那颗可怜而狡猾的心造成什么影响！
might do to your poor,
wittle heart!
别担心我 伙计 我会没事的
Oh, don't worry
about me, pal,
I'll be just fine.
既然这样我可以对你完全坦白了吗？
So since I can
be completely
honest with you?
Oh, please,
你就坦白地说吧
be completely honest.
(SCOFFS)
你觉得你配吗？
You think you
deserve a movie?
是的
Yeah.
在生活中 你除了观看并嘲笑它还做过什么？
What did you
ever do in life
but watch it
and mock it?
(SCOFFS)
你他妈做过什么？
What have you ever
fucking done?
我有过生活
I had a life.
我离幸福快乐的日子就差那么一点点了
后来一个醉酒的司机
I was this close
to happily ever after
and then, one drunk
driver later...
我的电影结束了
my movie's over.
永远
Forever.
没有幸福的结局
No happy ending,
没有续集
no sequel.
甚至没有第二次机会
Not even a third
fucking act,
就只是 “去你妈的！顺便说一句”
just, "Fuck you!
And, oh, by the way,
“去你的！”
"fuck you!" Credits.
但是
(SNIFFLES)
But, hey...
那跟心脏病比算什么？
What's that compared
to a heart attack?
我的意思是 该死的！
I mean, shit!
你差点就死了 对吧？
You could have
almost died, right?
对
Yeah.
那好吧 我们中的一些人确实是死了
Well, some of us
did die.
从那一刻起 我们中的一些人的内心就已经死透了
Some of us have
been dead inside
ever since.
但是 就在我每天走进这个地方
But then, just when
I'm able to walk
into this place
而不想自杀的时候
without wanting to
kill myself every day,
you have an idea.
你有个主意
你想拍一部关于你的人生的电影
You wanna make a movie
about your life.
你也说得很清楚了
Oh, and you...
you've been very
clear about that.
这是你的人生！
It's your life!
明白这一点 你这个以自我为中心
Well, get this,
you self-centered,
gaping wound
of a human being
而又永远都不会满足的人！
with your insatiable
fucking ego!
他妈的？
(SCOFFS) The fuck?
你的人生
Your life...
是我的人生！
is my life!
我一直都在你身边！
I've been
there with you
the whole time!
既然你知道我的生活有多艰难
And since you know
how hard that life's
been on me,
你有没有想过
did it ever
occur to you
也许我根本不想重温那该死的生活？
that maybe I didn't wanna
relive that fucking life?
所以 我不想再
So, I quit...
作你的制片人了
as your producer.
而且我再也不想
And I quit...
当你的朋友了
as your fucking friend.
(BREATHES SHAKILY)
因为我甚至不应该
'Cause I'm not
even supposed to...
(GRUNTS)
(BODY THUDS)
这就是我所说的表演！
Now that's what
I call acting!
来吧 大家 为此鼓掌
Come on, everybody,
clap it up for that.
好了 但丁 起来吧
Okay, Drinkie-Mc-Stinky,
get up.
但丁？
Dante?
嘿
Hey.
嘿！但丁！
Hey. Hey! Dante!
醒醒啊 伙计 嘿！
Wake up, man. Hey!
叫救护车！
Call an ambulance!
醒醒啊 伙计 但丁！
Wake up, man.
Dante. Dante!
但丁？
Dante? Um...
-打扰一下 我们是
-什么？
Excuse me. We're...
What the...
不 你不能在这里
No, you can't be
back here.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
好的 天啊
All right,
already. God.
他们刚把我们的朋友送进来
They just brought
our friend in.
他叫但丁希克斯
His name
is Dante Hicks.
他是那个在便利店倒下的醉汉
He's the drunk guy
that collapsed
at the QuickStop.
急救人员说
NURSE: Uh-huh.
The first
responder said
-他心脏病发作了
-好
he's having
a heart attack.
Okay, okay.
先生 您需要在外面等着
You need to wait
out there, sir.
一旦我们了解到更多信息
就会有人过来告诉您的
Someone will be by
to tell you more
as soon as
we know more.
(RANDAL SCOFFS)
谢谢你
Thank you.
这是我第一次拒绝耶稣的地方
(SIGHS) This is where
I first rejected Jesus.
是的 现在看看发生了什么
Yeah, and now look
what's happened.
回到这里真是太奇怪了
So weird to be
back here.
说说吧
Yeah, tell me
about it.
好吧 我要离开这里
All right, look.
I'm gonna get
out of here.
他们一说什么就给我打电话 好吗？
Call me as soon
as they say something,
all right?
等等 什么？你要去哪里？
Wait, what?
Where are you going?
我要回去继续拍我的电影了 伙计
I'm gonna go work
on my movie, man.
你的电影？
Your movie?
对啊 它都快完成了
Yeah, I mean,
it's almost done.
我留在这里对但丁也没有任何帮助
It's not like I'm doing
Dante any good
sitting around here.
我还不如回去拍我的电影
I might as well
go work on my movie.
你在开玩笑吧？即使是现在？
Are you kidding me?
Even now?
“即使现在”什么？
"Even now" what?
“哦 我的电影”
"Oh, my movie.
“我的电影！每个人都拍我的电影
因为它非常重要”
"My movie!
Everybody make
my movie
"because it's
so important."
现在不是模仿克里斯诺兰的时候或地方
(SCOFFS) This is neither
the time nor the place
to do an impression
of Chris Nolan.
我是在模仿你 兰德尔
I'm doing
an impression
of you, Randal.
我们在医院
We're in
the hospital.
-所以呢
-不
That's stating
the obvious.
No.
所以我的意思是
The obvious statement
right now would be,
“别管电影了 我最好的朋友在医院”
"Never mind the movie,
"my best friend's
in the hospital."
只是心脏病发作 我也经历过 他会没事的
It's just a heart attack.
I had one. He'll be fine.
操你妈的 兰德尔
Fuck you, Randal.
(SCOFFS)
去你妈的
Fuck you.
-怎么了嘛
-天啊 伙计
Come on.
God, man.
我曾经那么崇拜你 但你是最差劲的人
你知道吗？
I used to look up
to you so much
but you're the worst,
you know that?
世界上最糟糕的
The worst
in the world.
没有但丁先生就不会有你的电影
Mr. Dante made
your movie happen.
是我促成了我的电影
I made my
movie happen.
我有了制作这部电影的想法
I had the idea
to make the movie.
剧本是我写的 我也是那该死的导演
I wrote the script
and I'm the
goddamn director.
我让这部电影成真
I made this
movie happen.
都是我
It was all me.
-都是你？
-是的
Oh, it was
all you, huh?
Yeah.
好的
(CHUCKLES) Okay.
脱掉你那愚蠢的面具 兰德尔
Take off your stupid
mask, Randal.
嗯
Yeah.
因为我记得但丁先生所做的一切
Because I remember
Mr. Dante
doing everything.
他甚至打电话给恨他入骨的前未婚妻
He even called
his ex-fiancee
who hates his guts.
他拿他一半的便利店作为抵押
He put up his half
of QuickStop
就为了让你有钱拍你的蠢电影
just to get you
the money to make
your stupid movie.
等等
Wait a minute.
但丁从艾玛那里得到了我电影的钱？
Dante got the money
for my movie from Emma?
蓝色代码 7号床
MAN: (OVER PA SYSTEM)
Code Blue. ER 7.
但丁 我不知道艾玛的事
Dante, I didn't know
about Emma.
-我才知道
-你又来了？我说了什么？
I just found out.
You again?
What did I say?
-我真的不知道
-我说什么了？
I didn't know.
What did I say, huh?
-保安！
-他还好吗？
Security!
Is he okay?
离开这里 伙计 出去！
Get out of here,
man. Get out!
-他还好吗？
-出去！保安！
Is he okay?
Get out! Security!
好了 放开我！
All right.
Get off of me!
兰德尔 你要去哪里？
Randal, where
are you going?
(LE GRANDE FROMAGE
BY REBUILDER PLAYING)
♪ Skip amongst
The telephone lines
♪ Catch a frequency
To pass the time
♪ Anything's better
Than New Jersey
♪ Living along the turnpike
♪ Headed home
他妈的！
Fuck!
♪ With the smell of smoke
♪ We ran out of things
To say
♪ So let it unfold
♪ We pumped the tires full
♪ All our favorite songs
Were shitty anyway
♪ Anything's better
Than New Jersey
♪ Skip amongst
The telephone lines
♪ Anything's better
Than New Jersey
♪ Living along the turnpike
♪ I'd give anything
To go home
♪ I gave up everything
To leave
♪ I'd give anything
To go home
♪ I gave up everything
To leave
♪ I gave up everything... ♪
我觉得还需要再加点
I think it needs
more weed.
Hmm.
天啊 嘿
God. Hey...
我需要你帮助但丁
I need your help
with Dante.
但丁是谁？
Who's Dante?
The fuck do
you mean? Dante.
你他妈是什么意思？但丁啊
除了我 便利店的另一个人啊？
The other guy,
the guy in the QuickStop
who's not me?
等等 我以为他的名字是塞尔吉奥
Wait, I thought
his name was Sergio.
-他的名字不是塞尔吉奥吗？
-是他妈的但丁
Ain't his name Sergio?
It's fucking Dante.
你到底要不要帮我？
Are you gonna
help me or not?
一切为了我们的兄弟 塞尔吉奥
Anything for
our boy Sergio.
我需要偷偷溜进医院去找塞尔吉奥
I need to sneak
into the hospital
to get to Sergio,
所以我想要你们去分散他们的注意力
so I want you guys
to create a very
subtle distraction.
我在重症监护室拉了！
I took a poo
in the ICU!
我拉 该死的！
I took a...
Oh, shit!
嘿！嘿！
SECURITY GUARD: Hey! Hey!
♪ Give up everything to leave
♪ Anything's better
Than New Jersey
♪ I'd give anything
To go home
♪ Living along the turnpike ♪
(SONG FADES)
(MONITOR BEEPING)
但丁？
Dante?
嗨 老兄
Hey, man.
我想 既然你只能躺在这里
I figure, since
you're just
laying around here...
你这个心脏病发作的小模仿者
you little heart
attack copycat.
你会有时间看我们的第一部电影
You got time to watch
our first movie.
Huh?
你会看到我对我在店里说的
那些愚蠢的事情很不以为然
You're gonna see
I was way off
with that stupid shit
I said at the store.
我不可能
I never... never would
have made this
movie without you.
没有你 我不可能拍出这部电影
没有你 我什么都做不了
I never could do
anything without you.
我在这里 伙计 我就在这
I'm here, man.
I'm here.
我们一起看吧
Let's watch the movie.
(O WALY, WALY
BY GERARD WAY PLAYING)
这就是我眼里的你
This is the way
I see you.
你是我的《星球大战》的主角
You're the main character
in my Star Wars.
(SNIFFLES)
You're not the Dak.
你不是达克
你一直都是卢克
You've always
been the Luke.
你也是我电影的男主角
(VOICE BREAKING) You're
the hero of my movie, too.
你一直是我的英雄 但丁
You've always been
my hero, Dante.
♪ The water is wide
♪ I can't get over
♪ Neither have I
♪ The wings to fly
♪ So go and get
♪ Me to a boat
♪ To carry both
♪ My love and I
(VOCALIZING)
♪ There is a ship
(BECKY CHUCKLES)
♪ Out on the sea
♪ And loaded deep
♪ As it can be
♪ But not as deep
♪ As love am I
我们走吧
Let's go.
♪ Don't care if I
-走吗？
-嗯
Yeah?
Yeah.
♪ Should live or die...
(SIGHS)
那是我看过的最好的电影
That was the best
movie I ever saw.
但这还没有结束
But it's not over.
你不想看看结局是如何的吗？
Don't you wanna
see how it ends?
我相信导演
I trust the director.
他不仅是我最喜欢的电影制片人
He wasn't just
my favorite filmmaker...
♪ The wings to fly
他曾经也是我最好的朋友
He was my best friend.
♪ Me to a boat
(DANTE SNIFFLES)
♪ To carry both
♪ My love and I
(MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY)
怎么了？
What's goin' on?
(SNIFFLES)
你还好吗？嘿
You okay? Hey.
嘿！
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hey!
别他妈的离开我 伙计
Don't fucking
leave me, man.
不要离开我！
Don't leave me!
该死的 医生！
Oh, shit. Help!
(JUST BREATHE  BY PEARL JAM
INSTRUMENTAL PLAYING)
就在那时 好小偷说
And that's when
the good thief said,
”耶稣没有做错 而我们不过是贼”
"Jesus did no wrong,
whereas we are
but thieves."
偷屁贼是什么鬼？
What the fuck
are butt thieves?
我不知道你们中是否有人知道这一点
但我现在是撒旦教徒
I don't know
if any of you
know this
but I'm
a Satanist now.
虽然我可能是魔鬼的妃子
And while I may be
the devil's concubine,
我仍然相信天堂
I still believe
in heaven.
因为但丁先生是我认识的所有人中最好的人
And because
Mr. Dante
was the best person
that I ever knew,
我相信他现在就在天堂
I believe
he's in heaven
right now,
就像义贼鲍伯一样
just like
the good thief.
但丁的地狱
Dante's Inferno.
不
No.
但丁的天堂！
Dante's Paradiso!
是的
Si.
谢谢你 埃利亚斯
Grazie,  Elias.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I, uh...
我
我想了很多关于今天要在这里说什么
I thought a lot about
what to say here today.
我本来想从《可汗之怒》中
柯克给史波克的悼词中抽两句话
I was gonna pull
from the eulogy
that Kirk gave Spock
in The Wrath of Khan,
但我一直是《星球大战》的粉丝
but I've always
been more of
a Star Wars  fan
所以我应该说些类似于
so I should say
something like,
“愿原力与你同在” 或“这就是道”
"May the Force be with you"
or "This is the Way."
但我想与其引用一部电影
我更愿意转述已故的人的话
But I think instead
of quoting a movie,
I'd like to paraphrase
the departed.
我所说的死者 是指但丁希克斯
And by the departed,
I mean Dante Hicks,
不是非常完美的斯科塞斯照片
not the Scorsese picture
that was pretty perfect
直到最后那只老鼠的场景
right up until that
stupid shot of the rat
at the end.
不管怎么说
So in the words...
我认识的最好的人
(VOICE BREAKING)
...of the best guy
I ever knew...
“你今天甚至不应该在这里”
"You're not
even supposed
to be here today."
♪ Nothing you would take
♪ Everything you gave
♪ Hold me 'til I die
♪ Meet you on the other side
我向你保证 我们正在哀悼
进来吧 你这个小偷屁贼 这就是你的新职位
RANDAL: Come on in here,
you little butt thief,
and assume your
new position.
但这里是但丁先生的位置
But this was
Mr. Dante's spot.
好吧 毕竟你一直以来
是我最大也是唯一的粉丝
Yeah, well,
after all this time
of being my biggest
and only fanboy,
谁说你终于成功了
I'd say you
earned it.
此外 当我们还在穆比工作时就告诉过你
Besides, I told you
way back when
we worked at Mooby's
当但丁走了 你将成为我最好的朋友
when Dante is gone,
you're gonna be
my new best friend.
(CHUCKLES)
不 我不是
No, I'm not.
我还能和谁一起玩？
Who the fuck
else am I gonna
hang out with?
是你和我了 伙计
It's you and
me, buddy.
Oh, fuck.
他妈的
Well, look who it is,
Mr. Big Shit.
好吧 看看是谁 大狗屎先生
好吧 看看是谁 大阴蒂夫人
Well, look who it is,
Mrs. Big Clit.
优雅 我怎么一点都不惊讶呢？
Classy. How am
I not surprised?
我很惊讶会在葬礼看到你
I was surprised
to see you
at the cemetery.
你为了但丁飞过来的？
You flew up
for Dante?
好吧 我差点嫁给那个男人
如果是这样的话
Well, I did almost
marry the man,
and if I had... P.S.
他根本就不会在50岁之前死于心脏病
He wouldn't have died
of a heart attack
before he was 50.
是的 因为和你在一起一年后 他就会自杀的
Yeah, because
after a year
with you,
he'd have
killed himself.
我想我听说你也心脏病发作了
I think I heard
you had a heart attack.
我说得对吗？
Am I right?
那一定是他妈的气死你了
That must really
fuck with you.
但丁死了 但你还在这里
Dante's dead but
you're still here.
我猜他们说的是真的 兰德尔
I guess it's true
what they say, Randal.
只有好人会英年早逝
Only the good
die young.
我是欠了谁的要在这里听你的冷嘲热讽？
To what do
I owe the pleasure
of your entirely
unwelcome visit?
我借了但丁3万美元
I loaned Dante
30 grand
然后他把商店的一半作为抵押
and he put his half
of the store up
as collateral.
现在他走了
Now he's gone.
如果你不能把钱还给我
那我就是这个店的半个老板
And if you can't
pay me back,
I own half this shithole.
(SIGHING)
你怎么说 混蛋？
How big's
my clit now,
motherfucker?
哦 我可爱的撒旦
Oh, my sweet Satan,
把你的力量借给温顺的人
把我们从这个魅魔手中拯救出来
lend your might
to the meek
and deliver us
from this succubus.
什么？
What the...
(PANTING)
风筝飞了！
The kites are flying!
Ah!
我重复！风筝
I repeat!
The kites are...
-飞了！
-他会说话？
flying!
He talks?
-是的
-哦 我的上帝
Yes.
Oh, my God.
我的天啊！
Oh, my God!
-我的天啊！
-什么？
Oh, my God!
What?
风筝卖完了
The kites
are sold out.
他妈的风筝 上帝 风筝
The fucking kites,
God, the kites.
那些风筝
The Crimson
Kite NFT's,
我们为俱乐部做的风筝
the ones we minted for
the Crimson Crypto Club.
区块链昨晚将它们放上去卖
然后都卖光了
Blockchain put them
on sale last night
and they all
sold out.
所以？
So?
我们两个刚赚了
The two of us
just made...
一百万！
One million!
一百万美元！
One million dollars!
Ah!
-撒旦万岁！
-我是加密货币富翁了 婊子！
Hail Satan!
I'm crypto
rich, bitch!
我刚刚兑现了十万美元来显摆和购买性服务
I just cashed out
$100,000 just to
flex and buy sex.
-来 拿着
-靠
Here, take that.
Shit.
你打算用你的钱做什么 大E？
What're you gonna
do with your
money, Big E?
我永远无法在这个柜台后面赢得现在的位置
I'll never be able
to earn my place
behind this counter
但现在可以了
but now I can buy it.
Here's your sucking
这是你吸血的钱
blood money.
Oh!
现在 滚出我们的商店！
Now, get the hell
out of our store!
真行呢
Well played, clerks.
抱歉
ELIAS: Sorry about
the mess.
那来自《星球大战》
That was from
Star Wars.
我只是因为你和但丁先生
I only said it
'cause you
and Mr. Dante
-曾经谈论过《星球大战》才说的
-我知道
used to talk
about Star Wars.
I know.
很久以前
Long time ago.
在遥远的银河系
In a galaxy
far, far away...
(DOOR OPENS)
天哪 那是一大笔钱 你想买些大麻吗？
Holy fuck,
that's a lot
of money.
You wanna buy
some weed?
是的！我想买所有的大麻！
Yes! I wanna buy
all the weed!
这里是1万美元
Here's ten grand.
那会让你爽翻天的
Whoo! That's gonna
get you higher
than Godzilla's
asshole.
那些风筝在哪里？
Yo, where those
kites at?
就这这里 尊贵的客户
Right this way,
valued customer.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
Aye-yi-yi.
(SNIFFLES)
(I'M FROM NEW JERSEY
BY JOHN GORKA PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
我希望你现在能在这里 伙计
I wish you were
here, man.
♪ I'm from New Jersey
♪ I don't expect too much
♪ If the world ended today
♪ I would adjust
♪ I'm from New Jersey
♪ No, I don't talk that way
♪ I watched too much TV
♪ When I was young
♪ There are girls
From New Jersey
♪ Who have
That great big hair
♪ They're found
In shopping malls
♪ I will take you there
♪ I'm from New Jersey
♪ It's not like Texas
♪ There is no mystery
♪ I can't pretend
♪ I'm from New Jersey
♪ It's like Ohio
♪ But even more so
♪ Imagine that
♪ I know which exit
♪ And where I'm bound
♪ The tolls on the parkway
♪ They will slow you down
♪ New Jersey people
♪ They will surprise you
♪ 'Cause they're not expected
♪ To do too much
♪ They will try harder
♪ They may go further
♪ 'Cause they never think
♪ That they are good enough
♪ I'm from New Jersey
♪ I don't expect too much
♪ If the world ended today
♪ I would adjust
♪ I would adjust ♪
(UPBEAT INSTRUMENTAL
ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
孩子们！是我 凯文史密斯
Hey, kids!
It's me, Kevin Smith,
我非常感谢你能第三次
and I can't thank you enough
for making this third trip
和我一起来到便利店 谢谢你
to the convenience store
with me. Thank you.
这一次对我来说很令人兴奋
Um... This time's
exciting for me
因为这一次每个人终于可以
像我一直看过的《疯狂店员》一样
because this time everyone
finally gets to see  Clerks
看到《疯狂店员》
the way I've always
seen Clerks.
大多数人认为《疯狂店员》是一部黑白电影
Most people think that Clerks
is a black and white movie
说得没错 它是用黑白胶卷拍摄的
and they're right.
It was shot on black
and white film.
但其实对我来说 每当我看《疯狂店员》时
即使它是黑白的
But, to me,
whenever I watch Clerks,
even though
it's in black and white,
它总是以彩色的方式出现
the movie appears in color.
因为我过着那样的生活
Because I lived that life.
所以现在 多亏了李朗
And so now, thanks to Lee Ron,
你们都看到了便利店和它的周边
you're all seein' QuickStop
and the surrounding area,
但丁、兰德尔、杰伊和沉默鲍勃
uh, Dante, Randal,
Jay and Silent Bob
就如我从第一天起就一直看的他们一样
as I've always seen them
from day one.
充满了生动活泼的色彩
Um, in vivid, living color.
Uh, you know, QuickStop
is the unsung, uh, star
你知道 便利店
是所有《疯狂店员》电影中的无名明星
of all the Clerks movies,
if not,
要不然 就是以观影问答宇宙电影的中心
you know, the epicenter
of the View Askewniverse
films in general.
所有的故事
Um, all stories emanate
都源自那座小楼
and flow from that
little building.
当我在那里工作时
And when I worked there...
um, I hated it.
I didn't want to be there.
我讨厌它 我根本就不想在那里
我不想给别人打工 也不想在那里工作
I didn't wanna work
for somebody else
and I didn't wanna work there.
人们会进来 然后我会说 “哦 我的上帝”
And people would come in
and I'd be like, "Oh, my God,
“我居然需要等人吗？”
"I have to actually
wait on people?
“我只想看电视”
"I just wanna watch TV."
我甚至不想在便利店工作
I didn't even wanna work
at the convenience store.
我试图在RST影视找工作
I tried to get a job
at RST Video.
报纸上有一个广告
There was an ad
in the paper for it.
我去和托珀先生交谈
他说 “我看到你”
I went down
and talked to Mr. Topper.
He said... He goes,
"I see you have
“还有便利店的工作经验”
"convenience store
experience as well."
我说 “是的 我在很多便利店工作过”
I said, "Yeah,
I worked in a bunch
of convenience stores."
他说 “你愿意时不时地
在隔壁的便利店工作吗？”
And he goes,
"Would you be
willing to work
”因为那也是我们的”
"in this convenience
store next door
我当时想 “行吧 如果你需要帮助的话”
"from time to time because
we own that as well?"
And I was like, "Uh, yeah,
if you need help."
也因为如此
And, uh, famous last
words because it...
那是一份便利店的工作
it was a convenience
store job.
我上了他的当 我刚结束
He catfished me.
I just wound up
便利店的工作几个小时
working in a convenience store
with a couple of hours in...
在一家影像店里 被天堂戏弄
in a video store,
teased with paradise,
然后被引诱 被拉去卖东西
then seduced and abandoned
to sell, uh, goods.
所以在《疯狂店员》里 兰德尔说
“伙计 这份工作会很棒”
So in  Clerks, Randal says,
"Man, this job would be great
“如果不是因为那些该死的顾客”
"if it wasn't for
the fuckin' customers."
但在《疯狂店员3》的剧本中
Uh, but in the script
for  Clerks III,
我要给你读一些
I'm gonna read you a little
something that was there
我没有用在电影中的东西
that I didn't use
in the movie.
在最后的回调镜头中 你能听到
During the pullback shot
at the very end,
you hear John Gorka's
约翰戈尔卡的歌 《我来自新泽西》
beautiful
I'm From New Jersey.
真的太棒了
And it was so lovely,
我没有采用那一段 也没按照剧本要求
I left that moment alone
and didn't put in
加入司默德的声音
what in the script called
for, the voice of Smod.
那就是我 这就是你会听到的
That would be me.
And this is what you
would have heard.
“在兰德尔格雷夫斯的余生中”
"Randal Graves spent
the rest of his life
“只要他不拍电影”
"running QuickStop Groceries
“他都在经营便利店”
"whenever he wasn't
making movies,
”而他的每部电影”
"with each film
financed solely
“都是由赤红加密影业独家赞助的”
"by Crimson Crypto Studios.
“在放映他的最后一部电影时”
"At a screening
of his final film,
“阿斯伯里公园出版社让他”
"the Asbury Park Press
asked him
“总结他的生活”
"to sum up
a life spent satisfying
“他既满足了公众对香烟和苏打水的需求”
"both the public's demand
for cigarettes and soda
“在他著名的处女作《疯狂店员》后”
"as well as their appetite
for the many movies
“他又拍摄了许多电影 满足了观众的胃口”
"he made after
his celebrated
debut, Clerk.
“90岁的兰德尔格雷夫斯回答说”
"The 90-year-old
Randal Graves replied,
“我一直认为工作”
"'I always thought that jobs
would have been great
“如果不是因为那些该死的顾客会很棒”
"'if it weren't for
the fuckin' customers.
“但事实证明”
"'But as it turns out,
“这些工作是因为那些他妈的客户才很棒”
"'these jobs are great because
of the fuckin' customers.'"
他是认真的 我也是
He means it and so do I.
感谢每一个人
Thank you to everybody
那些曾经走过那家商店的大门
whoever walked through
the door of that store
让我心想
and made me think,
“应该有人把它放在他妈的电影里”
"Somebody should put this
in a fuckin' movie."
有人做到了 谢谢你
Somebody did. Thank you.
是的！
JAY: Yeah!